<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Anti-Levellers antidote against the most venomous of the serpents, the subtillest monopolizers. Collected by divers officers and soldiers of the army, and other honest people of this nation.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1652</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 118 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 22 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A75476</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing A3501</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E673_10</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R207181</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99866251</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99866251</idno>
            <idno type="VID">118516</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A75476)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 118516)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 103:E673[10])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The Anti-Levellers antidote against the most venomous of the serpents, the subtillest monopolizers. Collected by divers officers and soldiers of the army, and other honest people of this nation.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>43, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by John Macock, and are to be sold by Francis Tyton at the three daggers in fleetstreet, and Nathaniel Brook at the Angel in Cornhill,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1652.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Aug 7".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Levellers --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:118516:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>THE Anti-Levellers Antidote AGAINST The moſt venomous of the Serpents, THE <hi>Subtilleſt Monopolizers.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">Collected by divers Officers and Soldiers of the <hi>Army,</hi> and other honeſt People of this Nation.</head>
            <argument>
               <p>Having in our Conferences in and about the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minster,</hi> and as we have travelled and ſtay'd in divers places of this Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, where we have heard divers honeſt People complain of many Grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances (which we conceive deſerve Reformation;) For the juſt Deſires of whom, we have imployed our beſt Studies and Endevors in ſearching out what hath been propoſed by others for Redreſs of thoſe Grievances, which, as we have heard and conceive, have undone many people, and much impoveriſhed divers, and put others to exceſſive and great charge and trouble (who have been true and faithful Members of this Common-Weal;) Out of which we have drawn this <hi>Antidote,</hi> being an <hi>Abſtract, &amp;c.</hi> which we tender to the Conſideration of all the People of this Nation to write againſt, or for Support or Amendment of the ſame, or any part thereof, in convenient time. To the end and intent that any who pleaſe may joyn in Petition to the Supreme Authority of this Nation to have the ſame Enacted, being (as we conceive) matters of great Concernment.</p>
            </argument>
            <p>AN Abſtract of the principal matter (as neer as we can gather) of ſeveral Propoſitions and Propoſals, which we have found publiſhed, and written ready to be publiſhed, and moſt material, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning the extraordinary chargeableneſs and unneceſſary proceedings in the Law, and the inconveniencies which have happened thereby, ſo far as yet we can hear of to be amiſs, after our ſeveral and reſpec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tive Conferences about the ſame (not only in <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter,</hi> but in our ſeveral and reſpective Travels about this Nation ſince theſe Wars began) with divers ancient Counſel, Clerks and Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, having given over their practiſes, and others; whom by their
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:118516:2"/>diſcourſes we conceive and hold to be juſt in their profeſſions, and to have abhorred the unconſcionable dealings of the corrupt Lawyers, and Monopolizing Officers depending upon the Law, in their contri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vances of divers inconveniences and miſchiefs, by which we have heard many in Countries, Cities and Towns ſay, that they have been much grieved, and deſired redreſs: All which at large we have ready with a ſhort Collection and Obſervation after the firſt fourteen there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, and ſo conſequently in order after the other following the ſame reſpectively; whereby any man (as we conceive) though but of mean capacity and judgment, may well underſtand how the ſeveral millions of Mony, which formerly yearly have been exacted from the honeſt people of this Nation (by corrupt and unjuſt Lawyers, and Monopolizing Officers depending upon the Law) will be every year hereafter ſaved to them; if thoſe Propoſitions and Propoſals, with theſe herein laſt mentioned, were enacted.</p>
            <p n="1">1. That men not able to pay may not be arreſted upon feigned great Actions (and thereby many undone) before ſummons, according to the ancient Laws of this Nation; which undue courſes, and unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful practiſes, have been too often acted in theſe latter times.</p>
            <p n="2">2. That if Sheriffs, or Bayliffs, or ſuch like Officers, do not execute the firſt Writ (to them delivered) to arreſt, but delude parties, and take Mony or Rewards on both ſides, as they have frequently uſed for many years together, the ſecond may be directed and made to, and executed by perſons eſpecially to be elected by Suiters in ſuch Writs for ſuch purpoſe.</p>
            <p n="3">3. And the like for not ſerving of Executions.</p>
            <p n="4">4. And that any who ſhall claim the property of goods in the poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion of any other (againſt whom there ſhall be Writs of Execution to ſeize and ſell the ſame, or to levy the ſame for any debt or demand) may be examined upon Oath of the truth of the matter; And that the Sheriff ſhall make enquiry by Jury of the truth thereof.</p>
            <p n="5">5. And that they who of ſuch goods ſhall make ſuch claim, and the ſame ſhall be proved falſe, ſhall forfeit the value thereof.</p>
            <p n="6">6. And that no Officer ſhall be ſubject or liable to any action for viewing or ſeizing or ſtaying (till ſuch enquiry be made) of any goods which were or ſhall be in the poſſeſſion of the party Defendant, his Executors or Adminiſtrators, or reputed his.</p>
            <p n="7">7. That no poundage Fee may be taken for ſerving of any <hi>Elegit</hi> or Extent, the Officer being at no danger in executing the ſame; Or that to avoyd charge and trouble, any who have ſuch <hi>Elegit</hi> or Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:118516:2"/>may make his Entry and Claim upon any Lands or Tenements liable to the ſame, and then bring his Action of Ejectment or real Action, as the cauſe ſhall require, which he uſually is driven to after ſuch charge and trouble.</p>
            <p n="8">8. That every one committing any reſcuſs, or hindering of any Arreſt, or Execution, or Diſtreſs, ſhall be liable to the debt or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand concerning the ſame.</p>
            <p n="9">9. And that every one compellable and uſing to ſtay Felons, ſhall be ſubject and compelled to ſtay ſuch party ſo doing.</p>
            <p n="10">10. And that Hue and Cry ſhall iſſue, and go after every one of them; Or that the Inhabitants of the place where ſuch offence be committed to make ſatisfaction.</p>
            <p n="11">11. And that if the Hue and Cry go out and ſtay any where be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore it come to the Sea, the Inhabitants there to pay half, and where the Reſcuſſers or Reſcuſſed eſcape, the other.</p>
            <p n="12">12. That every one who ſhall hold any other out of the poſſeſſion of any Lands or Tenements, by the ſpace mentioned in the Propoſal at large, next after the time in which ſhall be ſhewed to him a Writ for poſſeſſion or ſeizin for the ſame under ſeal, to forfeit the value.</p>
            <p n="13">13. That every one who ſhal have an Execution againſt the goods of any other, and ſhew it to any having ſuch goods, and he hindering or forbidding the party having ſuch Execution from taking thereof, or claiming the ſame, to forfeit the value: And that party having ſuch Execution, to be impowered to take the ſame, if not interrupted or forbidden.</p>
            <p n="14">14. That Plaintiffs in Outlaries may have the benefit of them, and not be baffled out of poſſeſſion, after they have been at great charge in ſuing them out, and procuring ſpecial Writs thereupon to be exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cuted, retorned and tranſcribed into the <hi>Exchequer,</hi> and Leaſes there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon made, which hath been too frequent; and moſt Outlaries have appeared only meer Terrors or Bugbears.</p>
            <p>If theſe fourteen (that is to ſay) 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, &amp; 14. were Enacted, then would the occaſion of the Exactions by arreſting men upon feigned great Actions yearly be avoyded, the number of ſuch ſo yearly being eſtimated to above one thouſand in <hi>England,</hi> who one with another of them by the ſame occaſion have been yearly put to the charges, and damages, and defrauded of 20 <hi>l.</hi> apiece, which amounteth to yearly in <hi>England</hi> twenty thouſand pounds.</p>
            <p>And thereby beſides would be prevented the extraordinary charges
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:118516:3"/>of the unlawful Exactions and Extortions and fraudulent dealings of Under-Seriffs, Deputies, Bayliffs, Sergeants at Mace, and their hangers or Dependants on them, and ſuch like; whereby very many of the honeſt people of this Nation have had exacted and extorted from them yearly one hundred and twenty thouſand pounds; and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides, by the ſame means aforeſaid, have been defrauded of, and loſt ſo much more (that is to ſay) one hundred and twenty thouſand pounds, which may eaſily be known by computing the Pariſhes in <hi>England,</hi> and the number of ſuch like Officers; for every hundred of Pariſhes, and every of them one with another yearly, uſually ſo exact, and extort, and defraud, and be the occaſion of the loſs of as much more.</p>
            <p>There is above eight thouſand Pariſhes in <hi>England,</hi> and for every hundred of Pariſhes one with another ten Hundreds, Liberties, or Bayliwicks, or ſuch like places of a Bayliff or ſuch like Officer for e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very one of them; and beſides, a Hanger or Dependant on every one of them one with another (ſome of them having two ſuch, and ſome above,) upon which account it appeareth that for every hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred of Pariſhes there be eſtimated to be at leaſt ten Bayliffs, which for eight thouſand Pariſhes amount to eight hundred Bayliffs, every one of which uſually have yearly exacted and extorted one with an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other one hundred and fifty pounds [150 <hi>l.</hi>] otherwiſe they could not ſpend ſo liberally, and they and their families fare and live ſo de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liciouſly, as it is commonly known they have done, and do; and ſome of them being ſrugal, gain thereby great Eſtates, notwithſtanding the great Rewards, Gifts or (as they may more fitly be called) Bribes, which uſually they have given yearly for ſuch their Offices to the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpective Underſheriffs, and ſuch like Officers of Shires and Counties, which amounteth to yearly one hundred and twenty thouſand pounds [120000 <hi>l.</hi>] and their ſaid Hangers and Dependers on them beſides yearly have, and uſually do ſo exact and extort the third part, ſo much which cometh to fourty thouſand pounds [40000 <hi>l.</hi>] yearly.</p>
            <p>And there be alſo eſtimated to be two hundred Corporation Towns in <hi>England,</hi> and every one of them to have four Sergeants at the Mace, and as many Yeomen (as they call them) or Aſſiſtants (ſome of them having many more, as namely in <hi>London</hi> 36 ſuch Sergeants, beſides ſo many of ſuch Aſsiſtants or Yeomen) every one of which one with another, have uſually ſo extorted and exacted yearly above two hundred pounds [200 <hi>l.</hi>] (many Sergeants and Yeomen paying great ſums of Mony for their places, and yet ſpending much and living
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:118516:3"/>at high Rates, and ſome of them gaining great Eſtates, as aforeſaid) which (accounting four Serjeants for every Corporation of thoſe two hundred Corporations) amount to eight hundred ſuch Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeants, every one of which yearly ſo exacting and extorting Two hundred pounds (200 <hi>l.</hi>) ſuch exactions and extortions come to One hundred ſixty thouſand pounds, [160000 <hi>l.</hi>] beſides ſuch exacti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and extortions by ſuch Yeomen or Aſſiſtants to the third part as much yearly Fifty three thouſand three hundred thirty three pounds, [53333 <hi>l.</hi>] and odd money; and Creditors and Suitors Plaintiffs have been uſually put to further charges, beſides neglect of their buſineſſes in waiting on ſuch Officers, and procuring Setters or their ſervants to attend on them, there being in two hundred Corporations, and in forty Counties, which there be in <hi>England,</hi> above One hundred thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand Arreſts done (in which there have been ſuch waiting and at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending,) in every of which ſuch Creditor, Suitor or Plaintiff hath been at the charge of 20 <hi>s.</hi> at the leaſt, and in ſome 2 <hi>l.</hi> 5 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>l.</hi> or 20 <hi>l.</hi> (though in ſome leſs,) and therefore accounting 20 <hi>s.</hi> in every one of them one with another, then it amounteth to yearly One hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thouſand pounds, [100000 <hi>l.</hi>] beſides much more (that is to ſay) half as much at the leaſt hath been ſo exacted and extorted in waiting and ſetting for many, againſt whom proces have been, and no arreſt done, which amounteth every year to fifty thouſand pounds, [50000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>And over and above all theſe vaſt ſums of money the Under Sheriffs and Deputies within the forty Shires, and of as many Counties of Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties as make the number of fifty Sheriffs of Counties (which there be in <hi>England</hi>) uſually have yearly ſo extorted and exacted every one of them one with another eight hundred pounds, [800. <hi>li.</hi>] other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe they could not afford to pay ſo liberally for their places, and ſpend ſo much, and live in ſuch height in clothes and dyet with the beſt ſort as uſually they have done, and gain ſuch great Eſtates as di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers of the thrifty of them have done, beſides notwithſtanding their ſqueezings—in the Exchequer by others as bad as they themſelves be and have been, which yearly fifty times eight hundred pounds [800 <hi>l.</hi>] amount to every year forty thouſand pounds, [40000. <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The total of which ſeveral ſums being caſt up together amounteth to five hundred eighty three thouſand three hundred thirty three pounds, [583333 <hi>l.</hi>] and odd money.</p>
            <p>And theſe ſums concerning <hi>England</hi> only.</p>
            <p>Concerning <hi>Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> almoſt half as much (which have
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:118516:4"/>been and may be again ſo extorted and exacted when matters ſhall be at quiet there if not prevented) but reckoned only at two hundred ninety thouſand pounds, [290000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The whole is nine hundred ſeventy three thouſand three hundred thirty three pounds, [973333 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>For ſaving to the Common-weal of four parts to be divided into five of the ſums before mentioned, theſe <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals</hi> be drawn, and ſome of them publiſhed at large, One hundred ninety four thouſand ſix hundred ſixty four pounds, being the fifth part of the ſaid Nine hundred ſeventy three thouſand three hundred thirty three pounds, [973333 <hi>l.</hi>] and deducted out of the ſame, there then will remain Seven hundred ſeventy three thouſand ſix hundred ſixty nine pounds, [773669 <hi>l.</hi>] being four parts thereof ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation.</p>
            <p>And beſides, by the means aforeſaid, and the ſubtil devices, and craſty inventions and practices of ſuch extorting Officers, the honeſt people of this Nation have been deſrauded of, and loſt double ſo much, being One Million five hundred fifty ſeven thouſand three hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred thirty and eight pounds. [1557338 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>Which ſums being caſt up together amount to Two Millions three hundred thirty ſix thouſand and ſeven pounds, [2236007 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The ſubtil devices and crafty inventions of ſuch Officers are more particularly expreſſed in other <hi>Propoſitions,</hi> following next after ſome of the latter <hi>Propoſitions</hi> herein mentioned.</p>
            <p n="15">15. That any of the Counſellors, Clerks or Attorneys (who have practiſed or ſtudied in the ſuperior Courts at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> and there approved of for their Honeſties, Judgments and Experience in their reſpective Practiſes and Studies) as the Law is, may plead, act or do any thing according to their reſpective Callings, and not be hindred by Monopolizers, as hath been too often uſed of late years.</p>
            <p n="16">16. That Copies of Bills, Plaints, Declarations, Anſwers, Repli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations, Rejoynders, and Proceedings to iſſue after the ſame, may be delivered by the one party in the Suit to the other, or their reſpective Agents, therein to ſave charges, and the Monopolizers deſerted.</p>
            <p>And if theſe 15th and ſixteenth <hi>Propoſals</hi> were enacted, then would the exactions and extortions,<note place="margin">☞</note> by compelling the people to buy Law and Juſtice, in paying for Copies of Bills, Anſwers, Replications, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>joynders, and other proceeding thereupon, be quite abrogated, and the Drones ſo exacting and extorting them (that is to ſay) the ſix Clerks, and ſuch like vermin, left and deſerted as uſeleſs, and by the
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:118516:4"/>ſame means ſaved to and for the honeſt people of this Nation yearly Two hundred and ſixteen thouſand pounds, (216000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>The manner how the laſt mentioned ſums have been ſo yearly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted and extorted, and how the ſame may be ſaved to and for the ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſt people of this Nation, hereafter followeth, for the perfect under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding of the common people, how the ſix Clerks ſo extort and exact yearly Twelve thouſand pounds, (12000 <hi>l.</hi>) and their under Clerks above treble as much, being Thirty ſix thouſand pounds, (36000 <hi>l.</hi>) the whole whereof is Forty eight thouſand pounds, (48000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>The Offices of theſe ſix Clerks being accounted yearly to be worth Two thouſand pounds (2000 <hi>l.</hi>) and more apiece; and it is com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monly knonw, that their Under Clerks uſually have taken and take af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the rate of eight pence for every ſheet, which they have copyed for above four times more then they have accounted for to ſuch ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>min their Maſters (which by them hath been connived at in ſome of ſuch their Under Clerks, of their favorites and creatures, partakers and helpers of them in ſuch their wicked practiſes, though not in others of them, whom they have kept under like Spaniels:) And moreover, the enacting of the ſame fifteenth and ſixteenth <hi>Propoſals,</hi> if done, will extend to all other Engliſh Courts, or formerly or now ſo called, which have been or may be hereafter created to or for the ſame, or ſuch, or the like effect or purpoſe (there having been eight or nine more of ſuch in <hi>England,</hi>) and thereby ſave further to the ſame people of this Nation yearly ſo much more, being Forty eight thouſand pounds, (48000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>The total of which amounteth to Ninety ſix thouſand pounds, (96000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>And the ſame Exactions and Extortions by the ſame occaſion would be removed out of the Courts of the Common Law, (wherein although Declarations and Pleadings be nothing near ſo long, yet in the number thereof far exceed thoſe in ſuch formerly or now called Engliſh Courts, or Courts of Equity,) and thereby and by ſhortening Declarations, &amp;c. in the recitals of Writs, and taking away of unne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſary imparlances, ſaved for the ſame purpoſe as much or more then before is mentioned, being Ninety ſix thouſand pounds, (96000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>The total of all which ſums concerning theſe two Propoſitions for <hi>England</hi> only, amounteth to One hundred ninety two thouſand pounds, (192000 <hi>l.</hi>)</p>
            <p>In <hi>Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> beſides which have been and may be here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after,
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:118516:5"/>if not prevented, half as much, being Ninety ſix thouſand pounds, [96000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The total of all which ſums for all thoſe places amounteth to the Two hundred and ſixteen thouſand pounds [216000 <hi>l.</hi>] before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned.</p>
            <p n="17">17. That no motion or Petition ſhall be made and delivered againſt any until a Copy thereof be firſt delivered to him:<note place="margin">Then may the ſavo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rite Law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yers hang up their Gowns in the Hang<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans Ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>robe.</note> And that if he do not conſent to the deſire in ſuch Copy (he being thereby directed to a leading precedent in ſuch caſe,) then he to forfeit the parties charges and damages of delay in moving: And that if he ſhall conſent there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto, and not gain-ſay the ſame within a convenient time, that then he ſhall be compelled to perform the ſame as if the ſame ſhould be or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered.</p>
            <p n="18">18. That no Prohibition or Conſultation be moved for, unleſs ſuch Notes or Writings be delivered or left in ſuch manner and form as is mentioned in the <hi>Propoſitions</hi> concerning Motions and Orders.</p>
            <p n="19">19. That a penalty of one hundred pounds be impoſed upon every Maſter of the Chancery, and other Referree, for reporting contrary to any Book or Writing ſhewed to him, which by his order he may view; or for not reporting ſo much (as he ſhould) within the Books or Writings, being ſhewed where to find the matter.</p>
            <p>And likewiſe if the ſeventeenth, eighteenth, and nineteenth <hi>Propoſals</hi> laſt mentioned were enacted, then would the extorting and exacting of Regiſters, and Enterers up, and Drawers of Orders, and Rules, and Copies thereof, be for ever buried in Oblivion, and thereby yearly ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation the extraordinary charges which formerly they have been unneceſſarily put to, amounting to, as hereafter is particularly calculated or caſt up, to Six hundred forty eight thouſand pounds, [648000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>How the laſt mentioned exaxtions and extortions have been drawn from the honeſt people before mentioned, and they conſtrained to buy Juſtice, as hereafter is expreſſed for the perfect underſtanding of the common people thereof: In every leaf of every of the two Books for a year of the Regiſters in Chancery, there uſually be entered ten or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinary Orders made upon motions there; in both thoſe Books for one year there moſt commonly have been for many years paſt, and be, three thouſand leaves or more for every year; every of which Orders one with another hath been and is an occaſion of expences extraordinary to both parties therein concerned, five pounds by drawing and making ſeveral Copies of Breviates, and ſeeing of one Counſellor to begin, and
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:118516:5"/>another, or others, and ſometimes many, to ſecond ſuch motion, and drawing and copying <hi>Affedavits</hi> and Orders ſeveral times, and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tering the ſame, and by ſeeing Solicitors to attend ſuch Court about the ſame.</p>
            <p>And many times when there hath been counſel on both ſides, it hath coſt the other party anſwering ſuch Motion, as much as the party mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the ſame: And in many Orders longer then thoſe ordinary, there uſually is and hath been expended in counſel and attendance, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther charges thereabouts, in ſome 10 <hi>l.</hi> ſome 20 <hi>l.</hi> others 40 <hi>l.</hi> and divers more.</p>
            <p>And at hearings as much or more; ſo that by entering of long Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders in theſe Books there will be no leſs charges in the Orders of eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry leaf of thoſe Books, by reaſon of the great charges of thoſe long Orders.</p>
            <p>At which rate the charges of the Orders in every of thoſe leaves one with another, will amount to 40 <hi>l.</hi> at the leaſt, and ſo of every one hundred of leaves to four thouſand pounds, [4000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>And there being in thoſe Books of the Regiſters, as before is men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, three thouſand leaves, it will be found by multiplying forty by three thouſand, that the total will amount to One hundred twenty thouſand.</p>
            <p>And alſo in other Courts, now or late called Engliſh Courts, or Courts of Equity, and ſuch like, wherein Secretary hand been uſed in <hi>England,</hi> without <hi>Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> to as much, amount unto One hundred and twenty thouſand pounds, [120000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>Beſides the charges about divers motions which dye in the breed<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, and therefore no Orders made upon the ſame, which mount<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>eth this laſt mentioned ſum much higher; but in regard we can come to no certain knowledg thereof, we forbear to make any further calculation about the ſame.</p>
            <p>Both which ſums being added together, amount to Two hundred and forty thouſand pounds, [240000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>In <hi>Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> beſides which have been and may be here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after, if not prevented, half as much, being One hundred and twenty thouſand pounds, [120000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The total in <hi>England, Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland</hi> Three hundred and ſixty thouſand pounds, [360000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>In Courts at Law, or Courts which have been called Latin Courts, Rules or Orders, which have been and are above four times the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber more then the former, accounting ſo much only as by them hath
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:118516:6"/>been ſo extorted and exacted, as before is mentioned in the other Courts, called Engliſh Courts, or Courts of Equity, (becauſe there is not ſo much charge in ſoliciting, breviating, or entring Rules or Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, as in the former, nor altogether in counſel, yet too much) being Three hundred ſixty thouſand pounds [360000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>The Total concerning Motions, Orders, and Rules, &amp;c. amount to ſeven hundred twenty thouſand pounds [720000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>Out of which deduct the tenth part, being ſeventy two thouſand pounds [72000 <hi>l.</hi>] (which will be ſufficient for the performance of ſuch buſineſſes) then will remain ſaved to thoſe honeſt people yearly hereafter ſix hundred fourty eight thouſand pounds [648000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p n="20">20. That Witneſſes may be examined in all Courts by Commiſsi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, mutually to be choſen; But with this, That any concerned in any Suit (who will, may at his own charge) have any of ſuch wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes examined at any Tryal, hearing or inqueſt, taking or making.</p>
            <p n="21">21. That all Commiſſioners may be to hear and determine, or to certifie the doubt; and that if the parties to the Suit ſhall not agree of the truth of that which any witneſſs ſhall depoſe, then may the Commiſsioners compel the Sheriff to ſummon a Jury to try the ſame, and the Jury to be choſen as in the general Title of Juries, and the matter to be determined above upon reading the Certificate.</p>
            <p n="22">22. That no matter in Arreſt of Judgment ſhall be moved or aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned to be Error in any Declaration, Complaint, Bill, &amp;c. or Plea &amp;c. unleſs ſuch matter be firſt ſhewed where the miſtake is, and how the ſame ſhould be amended, as certain as if the ſame were amended, the Declaration, Complaint, Bill, Plea, and other things before therewith mentioned, were or ſhould be good in Law.</p>
            <p n="23">23. And the like concerning Demurrers, &amp;c.</p>
            <p n="24">24. That if any witneſs be ſick and weak, or travelling beyond the Sea, or there, the party concerned may deliver to the contrary party a Bill, and require his Anſwer to the ſame, and he to anſwer within the time mentioned in the <hi>Propoſals</hi> at large, and ſwear to it before the next Juſtice of the Peace; and after, or for default of An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>wer, the party to examine for the perpetual remembrance of men of the matter.</p>
            <p n="25">25. That publication may be in every Cauſe immediately, or ſome ſhort time after witneſſes examined, in ſuch manner and form as is mentioned in the <hi>Propoſals</hi> at large.</p>
            <p n="26">26. That the firſt witneſs, coming at the time and place of the Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution of every Commiſsion, may be firſt examined.</p>
            <p n="27">
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:118516:6"/>27. That no ſtay of Suit may be by reaſon of any witneſſes go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing beyond the Sea, unleſs ſufficient matter be made appear upon Oath what ſuch witneſs can ſay.</p>
            <p n="28">28. That tender of emends may be for walking with feet and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on a Replevyn after the Cattel in Pownd, with damages and coſts to that time.</p>
            <p n="29">29. That Diſtreſſes after Apprizement by Jury, if the owner of it doth not make ſatisfaction, or replevyn the ſame (within convenient time) the ſame may be ſold, &amp;c.</p>
            <p n="30">30. For retorning of the names of the Bayl and Caption with it upon the removal in to the Superior Court, and none other to be there put in.</p>
            <p n="31">31. That no Writ of Error be brought till after Error ſhewed and allowed by ſome Judg.</p>
            <p n="32">32. For retorning of impartial Jurors to try Cauſes, and for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voyding of Imbracery.</p>
            <p n="33">33. And a Remedy for giving too little Damages.</p>
            <p n="34">34. And againſt finding falſe Inqueſts, and chargeableneſs of ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Execution.</p>
            <p n="35">35. That if any perſon ſhall be ſummoned by Writ, or Warrant, to appear in <hi>Chancery,</hi> or ſuch like Court, and ſhall not, then he ſhall be arreſted, and detained not onely until he ſhall appear, but alſo to ſtand to the order of the Court: And that if the Plaintiff ſhall give ſecurity to make reſtitution after the Defendant ſhall appear, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bey the Order of the Court, and a hearing be, then the Court may proceed to decree and ſentence, and iſſue out Execution.</p>
            <p n="36">36. That ſuch Actions, as uſually upon motions have been drawn from Tryal at <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westminster</hi> into proper Counties, may be there layd at firſt, without troubling of poor men to come to <hi>London,</hi> ſome from the furtheſt parts from thence, to make oath to alter the Viſne, begging to and going from the City, and there during their ſtay; during which times the Countries and Cities have been filled with Beggers, and their Countries Buſineſſes left undone.</p>
            <p n="37">37. That no Beggerly Fellows or Shurks may make Executions a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt goods.</p>
            <p>Nor Writs for outing men of poſſeſſion of Houſes, Lands or Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments.</p>
            <p>Nor delivering men out of priſon for Debts or Duties, until they have ſatisfied the ſame.</p>
            <p>By permiſsion of which, divers juſt Debts have been loſt, and
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:118516:7"/>many thereby undance, and others thereby ſuſtained great loſs.</p>
            <p n="38">38. That no Beggerly Fellows may be permitted to plead falſe Pleas, unleſs they have or ſhall firſt put in ſufficient Bayl for payment of the Debt or Demand in queſtion, or yielding himſelf to priſon, or make or cauſe Oath to be made of the truth of ſuch Plea, or of his ability to ſatisfie.</p>
            <p n="39">39. That Coſts may be for the Defendants in Demurrers, after they have been perplexed, troubled, and put to great charges, and the Cauſes adjudged or conſidered of for them.</p>
            <p n="40">40. And the like in Prohibitions.</p>
            <p n="41">41. And upon iſſues of a Record or no Record.</p>
            <p>And furthermore, if the ſaid 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, and 41. <hi>Propoſals</hi> and <hi>Propoſiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons</hi> were Enacted, extraordinary charges by multitude of Tryals, Non-ſuits, Hearing, Fees of over numerous Counſel, Motions, Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts of Judgments by Motions, and Reverſals of the ſame by Writs of Error, and bringing Witneſſes many times to Tryals from far re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>more places from thence, and there ſtaying long in expectance of ſuch Tryals, ſometimes by the ſpace of two, three, four, or five days, to the great charge and trouble of the party bringing them, in their main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tenance and keeping them together, the ſame Witneſſes having been ſometime brought from the one of the Corners of this Nation to an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other fartheſt remote from thence, will be ſo abated and brought to that low ebb, that thereby will be yearly ſaved to ſuch honeſt people much Mony, which formerly every year by ſuch means they have been unneceſſarily put to in coming, as hereafter (for the plain under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding of the common people thereof) is expreſſed, and caſt up to ſix hundred ſeven thouſand nine hundred ninety and eight pounds [607998 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>It hath been obſerved by us, and thoſe from whom we have recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved intelligence, that it is very certain that there be above eight hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pariſhes in <hi>England,</hi> beſides <hi>Wales,</hi> the County of <hi>Middleſex,</hi> and the Cities of <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Westminster.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And that there hath been uſually tryed for every hundred of Pariſhes twenty Cauſes or Tryals at every Aſſizes both Winter and Summer, being fourty Tryals for every hundred of Pariſhes one year with ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther; and in troubleſom Champion or open places and Counties ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny more, and in ſome of them double ſo many, as divers have ſaid, and in very few or none leſs (though in encloſed and quiet places and Counties,) which amounteth to four hundred Tryals for every thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:118516:7"/>of Pariſhes, which cometh to three thouſand and two hundred Tryals in a year in the ſaid eight hundred Pariſhes; twenty pound ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence in every of which amounteth yearly to ſixty four thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand pounds [64000 <hi>l.</hi>] beſides the tryals at <hi>london</hi> and <hi>Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minster,</hi> which yearly cometh to the ſixth part of ſo much, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ten thouſand ſix hundred ſixty and ſix pounds [10666 <hi>l.</hi>] and odd mony.</p>
            <p>And in thoſe places every year, Summer and Winter Aſsizes, as many and more cauſes have been taken out to be tryed, but com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded before tryal (the charges of every one of thoſe tryed amount<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to 20 <hi>l.</hi> as before is mentioned, cometh to the ſaid ſixty four houſand pounds [64000 <hi>l.</hi>] And thoſe not tryed, being as many in number and many more, counſel being retained in moſt of them be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they be ſtayd, come to as much, being ſixty four thouſand pounds [64000 <hi>l.</hi> more.</p>
            <p>And in other Courts (which have been Latin Courts, or ſo called) there hath been uſually ſo exacted and extorted as much or more then in all the other Courts before mentioned, as hereafter is particularly expreſſed for the clear underſtanding of all the people of this Nation, which amounteth to Two hundred two thouſand ſix hundred ſixty ſix pounds [202666 <hi>l.</hi>] odd mony.</p>
            <p>All which for <hi>England</hi> only Four hundred five thouſand three hundred thirty two pounds [405332 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>And half as much in <hi>Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> beſides all the Exactions and Extortions before mentioned, as there have been, and as it is fear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed will be again, if not prevented, being Two hundred two thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand ſix hundred ſixty and ſix pounds (202666 <hi>l.</hi>) pa The Total of all which amounteth to ſix hundred ſeven thouſand nine hundred ninety and eight pounds [607998 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
            <p>Some more to be ſaved may be gathered out of the ſaid laſt men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals,</hi> but moſt of it is caſt up in the bottom of thoſe concerning Regiſters, &amp;c.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Charges particular of every Tryal one with another on both ſides, calculated for the clear underſtanding of the common People, of the before mentioned Account, as followeth, (that is to ſay;)</head>
               <p n="1">1. In every one of thoſe Tryals one with another uſually hath been
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:118516:8"/>expended by the Plaintiffs (beſides the Defendants charge) three pounds. [3 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
               <p>And by the Defendants one pound. [1 <hi>li.</hi>]</p>
               <p n="2">2. For Counſel at the Aſſizes the one with the other, on the one part 2 <hi>l.</hi> as much on the other, 2 <hi>l.</hi> (few or none under; ſome ſo expending for Counſel 20 <hi>l.</hi> 30 <hi>l.</hi> or 40 <hi>l.</hi>) So that ſuch expences in Counſel in every Cauſe one with the other may very well be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>counted to amount to Ten pounds. [10. <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
               <p n="3">3. For Witneſſes, to the number ſometimes of thirty, at other times twenty, ten, or five, and ſeldom under, ſtaying at the Aſſizes ſome of them four, five, or ſix days, and ſeldom under two days: So accounting in one of them with another to be ten in number, and to ſtay three days at an Aſſize, &amp;c. each of them one with another to ſpend ten ſhillings in thoſe three days, and ſo much in going to and retorning home from ſuch Aſſizes, ſome of them going from one of the corners of this Nation to another fartheſt diſtant or remote from thence, and very many going from their home to ſuch Aſſizes thirty or fourty miles, with hindring their buſineſſes, which amounteth to 20 <hi>s.</hi> apiece one with another, ſome of ſuch witneſſes being of great quality or Trading: The Total, Ten pounds. [10 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
               <p n="4">4. In Fees in Court one with another, one pound ten ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings. [1 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi>]</p>
               <p n="5">5. For making Breviats and Copies in ſuch Cauſes, one with ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, one pound. [1 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
               <p>The Total of the charges in every Cauſe tryed, twenty ſix Pounds and ten ſhillings. [26 <hi>l.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi>]</p>
               <p>And the charges extraordinary in Cauſes made ready for Tryal, and Records thereof taken out and ſealed (but not tryed) amount to as much or more then of thoſe tryed, being many more in number, deducting the Court Fee in ſome not tryed, being 30 <hi>s.</hi> apiece in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry of ſuch Cauſe; and 5 <hi>l.</hi> being half the charge of the witneſſes in every of thoſe Cauſes in their ſtay at the Aſſizes, in Cauſes there taken up by advice of Counſel, after they have had their Fees in the ſame: which account of theſe particulars made good, which is ſpent unne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſarily in ſuch Cauſes tryed, and made ready for Tryal in the Supe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rior Courts: All which, amounting to thirteen pounds five ſhillings, being half the before mentioned ſum of the ſaid twenty ſix pounds ten ſhillings, if the ſaid <hi>Propoſals</hi> laſt mentioned were Enacted, would clearly be ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation.</p>
               <p>And concerning County, Corporation, Hundred, and three weeken
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:118516:8"/>Courts, the Calculation following of the charges extraordinary of Tryals there will clearly evidence in the two hundred Corporations before mentioned, no leſs can be eſteemed; in ſome of the Courts, there being three or four, and in divers more, (though in ſome few of them ſome Courts may have diſcontinued, or ſeldom been held.)</p>
               <p>And in every of them Ten Courts in every year (very many of them having more, ſome one or two or more almoſt in every week of the year) which amount to two thouſand Courts in a year by this account one with another; many thinking many more ſuch be.</p>
               <p>And alſo in every of thoſe Courts one with another in every Court day may be accounted four Tryals, and dbouble ſo many put off by ſuch fraud and practiſes as be at large mentioned in the Preamble of the <hi>Propoſals,</hi> (there being ten Tryals or more on ſuch day in many of theſe Courts) which amount to ſixteen thouſand.</p>
               <p>And in every of thoſe ſixteen thouſand one with another there is cauſed expence extraordinary by ſuch Monopolizers, and exacted and extorted from both parties to every ſuch Suit, the one of them with the other, from the beginning to the end thereof, occaſioned by practiſes and plots, in the ſaid Preamble expreſſed, ten pounds; in ſome of them there being much more ſo exacted and extorted, and in divers ſo much or more then have been in any of the Superior Courts.</p>
               <p>And in the eight thouſand Pariſhes, there is in every of them a Hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red Court, or Three-Weeken Court, held every three weeks in the year for every ten of thoſe Pariſhes, which amount to eight hundred three Weeken or Hundred Courts in thoſe eight thouſand Pariſhes; beſides a County Court for every of the fourty Counties, held every Month for every of ſuch Counties yeatly: In every of which Courts have been very few or none regarded by the Judges, Stewards, or Sheriffs there, or ſuffered quietly to practiſe as Counſel or Attorneys in ſuch Courts, but ſuch as are, or uſually have been, were, or uſually be, Under-Sheriffs, Deputy-Sheriffs, Bayliffs, or ſuch like, (who uſually ſide with, or are linked or allyed to ſuch Under-Sheriffs, Deputies, or perſons, and partake with them in their Exactions and Extortions be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore mentioned;) and in ſome of ſuch Courts they Monopolize as much, as in the Corporation, and other Courts before mentioned; by which means ſeldom any other, but ſuch perſons before menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned, come to, or practiſe in ſuch Courts; and thereby thoſe Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nopolizing
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:118516:9"/>and ſiding perſons do what they pleaſe in Suits in ſuch Courts, and uſually cauſe the Suitors in thoſe Suits to pay what they luſt; or otherwiſe to betray their Cauſes, and ſo defraud them, and by thoſe means cauſe as much or more expences and charges, and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>act and extort in thoſe Courts laſt mentioned more then in the Corpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration and other Courts therewith before mentioned, which is caſt up but only to as much.</p>
               <p>In the like Courts (which have been and are like to be again in <hi>wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> if not prevented) there hath been ſuch yearly Expences, Trouble and Charges, Exactions and Extortions occaſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, to half as much as laſt before mentioned.</p>
               <p>Twenty Tryals for every hundred of Pariſhes, at 20 <hi>l.</hi> apiece, come to four hundred pounds. 400 <hi>li.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Double for Winter and Summer, eight hundred pounds. 800 <hi>li.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>For eight thouſand Pariſhes, beſides <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middleſex,</hi> eight times 8000 <hi>l.</hi> is ſixty four thouſand pounds. 64000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>A ſixth part ſo much more for Tryals in <hi>London</hi> and <hi>Middleſex,</hi> ten thouſand ſix hundred ſixty ſix pounds, thirteen ſhillings and four pence. 10666 <hi>l.</hi> 13 <hi>s.</hi> 4 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Total, eighty three thouſand eight hundred ſixty ſix pounds, thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>een ſhillings and four pence. 83866 <hi>l.</hi> 13 <hi>s.</hi> 4 <hi>d.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Half-as much in thoſe taken up after Counſel retained, Fourty one thouſand nine hundred thirty three pounds, ſix ſhillings and eight pence. 41933 <hi>l.</hi> 6 <hi>s.</hi> 8 <hi>d.</hi> pa For the Superior Courts the Total of all theſe, One hundred twenty five thouſand and eight hundred pounds. 125800 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Half as much for <hi>Ireland</hi> and <hi>Wales,</hi> Sixty two thouſand and nine hundred pounds. 62900 <hi>l.</hi> pa The Total of <hi>England, Wales</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> One hundred eighty eight thouſand and ſeven hundred pounds. 188700 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Two hundred Courts in a year in every Corporation, eight Tryals in every of them one with another ſixteen thouſand, ten pounds ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pence in every of them cometh to One hundred ſixty thouſand pounds. 160000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>As much in County, Hundred, and three Weeken Courts, One hundred and ſixty thouſand pounds. 160000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Total, Three hundred and twenty thouſand pounds. 320000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Half as much in <hi>Ireland</hi> and <hi>Wales,</hi> One hundred and ſixty thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſand pounds. 160000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Total in all Courts, Six hundred fourty eight thouſand and ſeven hundred pounds. 648700 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="42">
                  <pb n="17" facs="tcp:118516:9"/>42. For recording of Conveyances to preſerve Purchaſers from be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing defrauded of their Eſtates (purchaſed for mony) by former Sales of the ſame, or Statutes and Judgments, or ſuch like Incumbrances upon the ſame.</p>
               <p n="43">43. And for prevention of Executors and Adminiſtrators from be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing put to pay Debts out of their own Eſtates, to their undoing, after they have payd as much as the Teſtators or Inteſtates Eſtates have a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mounted unto.</p>
               <p n="44">44. And for ſaving of many Debts, which Creditors, Deviſees, nd Legatees have loſt, and like to loſe.</p>
               <p n="45">45. For Preſervation of many Ships, which have been fraudulent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly over-charged with Engagements upon the ſame (called <hi>Bottomre</hi>) by wicked and unconſcionable Perſons ſailing in the ſame, and after by them wilfully run a-ground, and thereby (beſides the loſs of the Ships) the Creditors defrauded above the value thereof.</p>
               <p>If theſe 42, 43, 44, and 45, were Ordained, there would be no leſs then one million [1000000 <hi>l.</hi>] beſides twenty thouſand pounds [20000 <hi>l.</hi>] in the abatement of the charge of Conveyances, yearly ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation, (as we are informed by moſt with whom we have conferred about the ſame,) for then could no man be ſo defrauded as formerly; but ſuch things would be prevented in manner and form as is mentioned in the ſeveral <hi>Propo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals</hi> at large publiſhed concerning the ſame: for now of late few can rely upon the Oath of any, to a Bill exhibited againſt him in <hi>Chancery,</hi> for diſcovery of Incumbrances (which hath been formerly accounted a good courſe before divers unconſcionable peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple have grown too crafty,) many falſe Oaths of late having been made to ſuch Bills, and the parties thereupon relying, defrauded of many great ſums of Money: And divers people (who have continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in Debt ſeveral years together, and ſome of them borrowed Mony (upon Lands and Tenements of griping Uſurers) for far leſs then the value thereof) have been conſtrained to forgo the ſame for ſo much only, by reaſon ſuch needy perſons uſe to incumber ſuch Tenements with Bargains, Sales, Leaſes, Annuities, Statutes and Judgments, and other Incumbrances; that few dare meddle with the ſame, but at an under-value, ſometime at half, and at other times at leſs then the value thereof: and divers (who have delt with mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cileſs Creditors) have had their Woods cut down, and ſold at a very ſmall value, and their houſes demoliſhed, and their Lands and Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments extended at ſmall rates; and thereby many others of the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:118516:10"/>have either loſt, or come ſhort of their Debts; and ſuch poor people, their wives and children, utterly undone: All which the Enacting of thoſe <hi>Propoſitions</hi> would prevent; and ſave many ſhips from periſhing, and preſerve many Executors and Adminiſtrators from undoing (by paying Debts out of their own Eſtates, after they have formerly payd as much as the Eſtates, which have been of ſuch Teſtators and Inteſtates at the time of their deceaſes, came to;) And many Creditors of other ſuch Teſtators and Inteſtates from loſing their Debts.</p>
               <p n="46">46. That poor Priſoners, not able to pay, may be let out, till they ſhall become of ability.</p>
               <p n="47">47. That the Eſtates of Priſoners of ability may be ſold to ſatisfie their Debts, notwithſtanding their lying in Priſon.</p>
               <p n="48">48. And that thoſe lying in Priſon, and fraudulently concealing their Eſtates; or which wilfully ſhall conſume the Eſtates (which they ſhall get into their hands) of others may be ſtrictly held to work for the benefit of their Creditors, till ſatisfaction given, or agreement made with them.</p>
               <p>If theſe 46, 47, and 48, <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals</hi> were Enacted, then would be ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation to the value of three hundred thouſand pounds [300000 <hi>l.</hi>] at leaſt, yearly here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after; beſides yearly ſaving of Debts (which formerly every year have been loſt) to as much, as we are informed by moſt, and by o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers to as much more, and by others to double ſo much; there be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or uſually having been, as we are informed by thoſe (who ſpeak to the leaſt) the number of twelve thouſand Priſoners yearly; every of which Priſoner one with another waſteth and conſumeth yearly above 30 <hi>l.</hi> which amounteth to three hundred and ſixty thouſand pounds [360000 <hi>l.</hi>] of which will be ſaved to the honeſt people of this Nation above three hundred thouſand pounds [300000 <hi>l.</hi>] Be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides the prevention of Frands (which uſually have been hatched in Priſons, by long Liers there) whereby divers have been utterly de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frauded of their juſt Debts, Duties, Demands and Damages, amount<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, as is eſteemed by ſome, to ſo much, by others to double ſo much; All which, and the Remedy thereof, more plainly and at large are printed and publiſhed.</p>
               <p>By theſe, as they who gueſs loweſt eſteem, ſaved yearly, Three hundred thouſand pounds. 300000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Beſides loſs of Debts and Damages to as much, Three hundred thouſand pounds. 300000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:118516:10"/>
               <p>By the mean as much more, Six hundred thouſand pounds, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides &amp;c. 600000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>By the higheſt to treble, Nine hundred thouſand pounds, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſides &amp;c. 900000 <hi>l.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="49">49. That a Demand in writing (and no Denyal to that by the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſent to) may continue an Action without ſpeciality, and may be ſufficient for that purpoſe, as well as to commenſe chargeable Acti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to Infinites, to the utter undoing of many; very many, by the nicety of the expoſition of the Statute in ſuch caſe provided, having loſt the greateſt part of their Eſtates.</p>
               <p>If this in the ſaid 49<hi rend="sup">th</hi> were Enacted, we conceive, and are cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dibly informed, would be ſaved (beſides in unneceſſary Expences in Suits) by the preſervation of many from the loſing of many juſt Debts, Duties and Demands, to the value of many thouſands of pounds yearly, as we conceive, Two hundred thouſand pounds, [200000 <hi>l.</hi>]</p>
               <p n="50">50. For the Enlargement and Explanation of the Statute againſt Bankrupts, and that it may be, that after the appearance of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt before the Commiſſioners, he may nominate and have an equal number of Commiſſioners for him to be joyned with the other to ſpeed on the buſineſs, and ſave charges, and ſee fair carriage,<note place="margin">☜</note> that the Bankrupts Eſtate may go and be imployed to and for the ſatisfaction of the Creditors, and not waſted by Commiſſioners in feaſting and wine, and the Creditors little the better, as often hath hap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pened.</p>
               <p>If this Fiftieth were Enacted, it would ſave half of that, which uſually is ſpent in the Execution of Commiſſions upon ſuch Statutes, and more, (many having been undone thereby, both Bankrupts (or ſo ſuppoſed) and Creditors) which amount to many thouſand of pounds yearly; beſides the prevention of divers Injuries and Wrongs, which have been done by many inſolent and wicked People of mean and beggerly condition (ſome of them having been Cutpurſes and Thieves) by breaking into Houſes, and carrying away the Goods of divers quiet People, wounding and maiming divers of them, and of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fering great violence to, and affrighting others of them, by colour of authority of ſuch Commiſſioners; whereby many ſuch quiet People have ſuſtained loſs to great value, which we are informed, and do believe, with the other Expences which hereby may be prevented: But the <hi>Propoſition</hi> for Foreign Attachments in the former <hi>Propoſals</hi> mentioned, and that for Writs of Juſtice after recited, together with
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:118516:11"/>ſome other of the <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals,</hi> will render moſt Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions going out upon thoſe Statutes unneceſſary, and thereby the greateſt part of the exceſſive charges exacted, amounting to many thouſand of pounds yearly, reſerved for the benefit of the Honeſt: wherefore we forbear to make further inquiry of the certainty to be ſaved by the reſidue of ſuch Commiſſions as hereafter may be uſeful, if, this <hi>Propoſition</hi> ſhould be Enacted, though we are informed that ſo to be ſaved will amount to many thouſand of pounds more; the Sum to be ſaved by the reſidue amounting to ſo much, and riſing ſo high, as before is mentioned.</p>
               <p n="51">51. That Judgments and Statutes may take hold on Copy or Cuſtomary Lands, and be liable to and for the ſatisfaction of Debts, as far as they are by the Statute of Bankrupt.</p>
               <p n="52">52. And alſo of Debts and things in Action.</p>
               <p>If this in theſe 51, and 52, were Ordained (we are informed, and do conceive) would thereby much more be ſaved over and above that which would be ſaved by the former: But there being ſo much to be ſaved by thoſe (as in our thoughts is high time to remedy) we forbear to caſt up what may be ſaved by theſe.</p>
               <p n="53">53. That <hi>Parliaments,</hi> or <hi>Repreſentatives,</hi> may be choſen by the love and affection of the honeſt People of this Nation, capable for ſuch choyce, without trouble or charge to thoſe to be choſen, and very little to thoſe to chooſe.</p>
               <p>If this were ſo, then would not any be at ſuch charges about their Elections, as many have been, ſome having been at the charges of 400 <hi>l.</hi> 500 <hi>l.</hi> and ſome 1000 <hi>l.</hi> or more, about their Elections to ſuch imployment; which, as many conjecture, in the choyce of the whole number for one Parliament, hath amounted to one hundred thouſand pounds [100000 <hi>l.</hi>] being divers (who have been at ſuch expence) have been layd aſide, and others choſen for ſuch imploy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
               <p n="54">54. That no Felons may hereafter be put to death for petty Felo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies (the ſame having been more frequent in latter times then in anci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent,) and being not ſo rigorous in other places, but that for ſuch pet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty things they may be compelled to give to, and work for competent ſatisfaction for the parties to be grieved in the firſt place, and after for the benefit of the State; which will more benefit the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monweal then taking away their lives, and prevent more ſuch Felonies.</p>
               <p n="55">55. That Taxations of Pariſhes may go equally upon Eſtates, both
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:118516:11"/>Real and Perſonal, of every one alive reſpectively, according to ſuch Reſpective Eſtates and Debts owing to or by any, that the poorer ſort, or ſtrangers, may not be oppreſſed, as hath been too frequent.</p>
               <p n="56">56. That Tythes may no more be payd or exacted out of errable Lands, nor in any unreaſonable manner.</p>
               <p>All which <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Propoſals,</hi> not yet publiſhed, are ready to be printed and publiſhed in convenient time.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>The Sums of Mony which may be ſaved to the Honeſt of this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion every year hereafter, as formerly yearly have been exact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and extorted from them; And of yearly Loſſes of Estates prevented hereafter (which in thoſe former times annually have been,) as they are respectively caſt up in ſeveral Places before mentioned.</head>
               <p>
                  <table>
                     <row>
                        <cell>LOSSES in Eſtates prevented</cell>
                        <cell>By the <hi>Propoſitions</hi> and <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſals</hi> reſpectively hereafter recited</cell>
                        <cell>Mony exacted and extorted, Saved.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1557338 <hi>li.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14.</cell>
                        <cell>778669 <hi>li.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>15, 16.</cell>
                        <cell>216000 <hi>li.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>17, 18, 19.</cell>
                        <cell>648000 <hi>li.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell> </cell>
                        <cell>20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 41.</cell>
                        <cell>648700</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>1000000</cell>
                        <cell>42, 43, 44, &amp; 45.</cell>
                        <cell>020000</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>0300000</cell>
                        <cell>46, 47, &amp; 48.</cell>
                        <cell rows="3">300000</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>0200000</cell>
                        <cell>49, 50, 51, 52.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>0100000</cell>
                        <cell>53.</cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Tot.</hi> 3157338 <hi>l.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>The Total of Mony ſaved, and Loſſes in Eſtates prevented 5768707. <hi>l.</hi>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                           <hi>Tot.</hi> 2611369 <hi>l.</hi>
                        </cell>
                     </row>
                     <row>
                        <cell>Three millions one hundred fifty ſeven thouſand three hundred thirty and eight pounds.</cell>
                        <cell>Five millions ſeven hundred ſixty and eight thouſand ſeven hundred and ſeven pounds.</cell>
                        <cell>Two millions ſix hundred and eleven thouſand three hundred ſixty and nine pounds.</cell>
                     </row>
                  </table>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:118516:12"/>
               <head>Here follow Ten Additional Propoſitions (in ſupply of the former) with our Obſervations upon the ſame.</head>
               <p n="1">1. <hi>THat no Monopolizer, but any (who have practiſed or ſhall practiſe as Clerk by the ſpace of ſeven years or more in any of the Superior Courts, and no Exception ſufficient to diſable him in that behalf) or other (who have practiſed or ſhall practiſe in ſuch Court a leſs time, and be accounted an able Clerk in ſuch Court for drawing and contriving any thing in or concerning the ſame Court, and to be honeſt in his dealings) may draw, or contrive, or act any thing properly to be done in ſuch Court by any Clerk; and that if any Monopolizer take upon him to exact any thing for acting in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, and to exclude any from having any other but himſelf for his Clerk or Attorney, ſuch Monopolizer to forfeit to the party grieved the value of the juſt Debt or Duty, for which he ſhall go about to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecute.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>By this, if the ſame were Enacted, the Offices for making Writs under pains, and <hi>Affidavit</hi> Offices, and divers other unneceſſary Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices, would be rendred vain and uſeleſs, and proceeding in Suits gone through with more eaſe and leſs charge, and underſtood by many more then can be now; the Monopolizing Officers in ſuch Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices having contrived ſuch contrarieties of proceeding in them, that few or none can or could underſtand the ſame, without the aſſiſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of ſuch Monopolizers, which they have uſually kept ſecret from all, except their aſſociates, or creatures in whom they uſe to put con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fidence, and from whom they uſe to receive Rewards, or as they more fitly may be called, Bribes, without diſcovery thereof to any; and theſe and thoſe know the meaning of each the other, (that is to ſay) the one of them by the looks and countenance of the other of them: And ſuch Officers, or Jacks in Office, have been very inſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lently proud, and accounted ignorant in any thing, but contriving of means for ſupport of their Exactions and Extortions; And when they have overthrown many good Cauſes by their own neglect, or wilfully for their own gains, they have layd the fault upon the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecutors of ſuch Cauſes, who have been honeſt and careful therein; and who by the favor, which ſuch Officers have gained of their Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>periors, have been kept ſo under, that ſeldom they durſt complain in
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:118516:12"/>that behalf; and when they have complained, have been ſeldom heard, relieved, or believed, though they have made the matter never ſo ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parent and clear.</p>
               <p n="2">2. <hi>That the matter to be anſwered unto, of all ſpecial Writs, may be put into Bills, Plaints, Declarations, Counts, or Informations, as large as ſuch Bills have formerly been uſed to be made, and that to be and ſtand for all Bills, Declarations, Counts, and Informations, (which ſhall be in the ſame till the matter of the ſame be or ſhall be tryed,) and that the Writs (which be or ſhall be made concerning any ſuch matter) ſhall be made againſt the parties (againſt whom the ſame be or ſhall be ſued out) to appear to and anſwer the matter of ſuch Bill, or other thing therewith before mentioned, or to do or perform as by Law ought to be done concerning the ſame; and that every Sheriff (to whom the ſame be or ſhall be directed) ſhall do as he be or ſhall be commanded by ſuch Writ, and retorn the ſame into ſuch Court, from whence the ſame ſhall iſſue with ſuch Bill, Decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, Count, or Information therewith ſent or to be ſent.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Then would all the Curſitors be rendered unneceſſary, moſt of them (as is generally reported) not knowing how to do any thing but what is contained in the Book called <hi>The Regiſter of Writs,</hi> which every Clerk of ability knoweth how to do, as well or better then any of ſuch Curſitors, who have lately gained much for doing little, they being formerly only ſervants to the ancient learned Maſter Clerks, who themſelves in their times lived only upon ſmall Penſions or Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lary allowed them out of the Publique Treaſure, and had nothing elſe for doing buſineſs in their Offices, their Means being ſo ſmall, that in a dear year they were conſtrained to Petition to the King for a peny in a day allowance more, and having obtained the ſame, and the dearth expiring and plenty following, they became to be ſo negligent and laſcivious, that Suitors could not have their buſineſſes diſpatched as formerly they had, whereby the people petitioned unto the King to have that ſuperfluous allowance taken away; but they being part of the Clergy held as a Maxim to hold that which was given to the Church, and not to depart from it, whereby Addreſs and Complaint was made to the Pope, who decreed, That if they did not follow their duties as formerly they had done, they ſhould have corporal puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment by Gelding;<note place="margin">☜</note> and this hath been always the fruit of ſuperfluous allowance to Officers: for ſince the Expiration of thoſe ancient learn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Maſter Clerks, when any ſpecial Writ hath been to be made in the Office of or by ſuch Curſitors, if the Proſecutor thereof hath not pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cured
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:118516:13"/>the ſame to be drawn by learned Counſel or Clerks, they ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom or never could have any of the ſame done by any of ſuch Curſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, and few or none of ſuch Curſitors have been heard of to be of ability to do any ſuch thing, ſince the Succeſſors of Maſter Clerks, now called the Maſters of the Chancery, have been taken up in mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters of Accounts and References of great benefit, and yet one part of thoſe who formerly were their puples or ſervants (now called the Six Clerks) have far out ſtripped them in wealth, by doing nothing beneficial to the Publique, but miſchievous.</p>
               <p>And now ſuch Maſters of the Chancery are become ſo unfit for the Imployment, as the ancient Maſter Clerks have done, that they are al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>together ignorant in performance of the ſame, and uſeleſs as to that; and ſo conſequently all the Curſitors, Philazors, Exigenters, and Clerks, and office of Utlaries, rendered totally needleſs, and therefore ſuch Offices may well go to better Imployment.</p>
               <p n="3">3. <hi>That all Writs Judicial hereafter may be made out of every Court by ſome of the Judges there, his or their Clerk of the Court, proper for making or iſſuing forth of ſuch Writs, or at leaſt by one of them, if ready written, examined, and rejected if ill done, and ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>proved of and ſigned if well done, without taking any thing for ſo doing.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And this may ſuch Judges very well afford to do out of the large Salary allowed to them, and live civilly as their Predeceſſors did, when they rode from the Serjeants Innes to <hi>Westminster</hi> Hall and back a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain upon Aſſes,<note place="margin">To ſhew they ought to be hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble.</note> and not to vaunt as ſome have done, nor to hoard up much as others have done, who with their Favorites and Creatures have gained exceſſively by the Law before, and grew mighty in riches, as did the Papal Prieſts before their fall, (who in their times gained a great part of the beſt Lands and Scituations of this Nation by Combi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, Craft and Subtilty, by lulling the people aſleep in ignorance and blindneſs in their vain Superſtition, pronouncing Hell and Damnation with Bell, Book and Candle to all who did not obſerve the ſame, and thereby brought the people into a ſond belief of them,) for ſince that fall, thoſe (that is to ſay) the Judges and their favorites, have far out-run theſe Prieſts, in gaining riches in an exceſſive manner by griping of very many men, (divers of whom having been very indigent perſons,) and have climbed up and leap'd into moſt of the Lordly Titles and gainful places and offices in this Nation, and therein and thereby have domineered, tyrannized over, and oppreſſed the honeſt people, and gained the favour of fawning, flattering, and laſcivious Courtiers by
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:118516:13"/>rewards, which they have given upon their entrance into and upon the extorting, exacting, innovate, unneceſſary Offices in this Nation, to ſuch laſcivious and fawning Courtiers and Sycophants, who, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding that which they had of them at the firſt, have cauſed ſuch Officers, and great perſons, and inferior innovated Officers under them, to bleed every year,<note place="margin">☜</note> and vomit up part of their Extortions and Exactions, to continue them in ſuch their pride and luſt; and in thoſe ancient times the Serjeants, or Servants at Law, though they were very learned, and far excelled many which have been ſince, and took great pains and care, received very reaſonable for the ſame, and yet were glad when Clients retained them, and uſed them mildly,<note place="margin">Their Fee in ancient times but ten groats for a Term.</note> and had great care of their buſineſſes, ſeldom times any Lawyer taking above one Fee in one Cauſe in a Term, notwithſtanding ſuch care and pains; for then they did not cauſe men to ſtand Cap in hand, and ſcrape legs, and beſeech them to take their mony, and then to take large Fees of them; moſt commonly twenty ſhillings, and many times more, and divers times many pounds, and divers and ſundry times have done lit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle, and ſometimes nothing at all for the ſame, nor came at the Bars at all at the times and places where and when they were to ſpeak ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their Retainers; and yet when ſome few of them have been required to reſtore the mony which they ſo have taken, they have been ſo impudent as to refuſe, and have denyed to reſtore the ſame, ſaying to the Clients,<note place="margin">☜</note> it was enough for them that he were not againſt them, and chid them away, who have not dared to complain againſt ſuch Lawyers by reaſon of the favour which they have had with great Parſonages, to whom properly ſuch Clients ſhould com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plain in that behalf, being in great places, and having acted ſuch things before they had climbed thither, by which means many have been ruined, out of whoſe decays ſuch Serjeants and Lawyers of late have made, at their entrances into their offices or places, princely Feaſts, at which they entertained many Sycophant laſcivious Courtiers, and thereby ſo ingratiated themſelves with thoſe and the lordly perſons of this Nation, that they have come to ſuch powerful and gainful places as is before mentioned, and as is reported were the chief Procurers of a Law to be made, whereby they be ſtiled the honeſt Serjeants, &amp;c. and that nothing ſhall be allowed to any Attorney for any thing gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to any Lawyer, unleſs he hath a Ticket or Note under the hand of ſuch Lawyer to ſhew for the ſame, which whether any, or any conſiderable number, did or would give any ſuch thing of late, any reaſonable man may judg; for it is doubted they are aſhamed to give
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:118516:14"/>any ſuch Note, their Fees having been of late ſo large; but by theſe means the poor Attorney is kept in a ſlaviſh condition, that he dareth not ſpeak what he knoweth, for fear that if his Clients (who will not willingly pay for what he paid to ſuch Serjeants and Lawyers) but he be conſtrained to ſue for the ſame, and cannot fright his Clients into payment, he ſhall ſurely loſe his mony before he can obtain ſuch Note from any ſuch Lawyer: And now of late the Attorneys are not per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted (as anciently hath been uſed) to read Records at Aſſizes, when there have been very few Records <hi>Niſiprizes</hi> tryed in ſome Counties (where many of late uſe to be tryed) not above one or two in two or three years, it having been a wonder to the people in divers Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to hear of ſuch a thing tryed there, and in thoſe ancient times there ſeldom or never was any Counſel on either ſide at ſuch Tryal, but the Judges (being then very learned) cauſed the Attorneys to call their Clients Witneſſes, and he diligently examined them in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of the Jury, and after ſull evidence heard, informed the Jury what he conceived they were to do, according to his duty, in which ſuch Judges in thoſe days were very diligent, and did not ſit ſleeping while the Evidence were giving, and leave the Debate of the buſineſs to many Counſel on both ſides to wrangle and ſcold out the matter, which often hath been done in ſuch manner, as the Juries have found againſt the right, as hath appeared afterwards.</p>
               <p n="4">4. <hi>That all Records, which ſhall be needful to be made and bound up into Books or Bundles, ſhall be written by the Clerk or Clerks of ſome of the Judges of ſuch Court, or Examined and Signed, and done within ſuch manner and form, as is mentioned in the ſaid third Propoſition, without taking any thing for the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And this may ſuch Judges very well afford to do, or cauſe to be done, out of their great Allowances or Salaries which now are given and allowed unto them, as well as the former; for in ancient times when the former Judges had but ſmall Salaries (in reſpect of that which is now allowed to theſe Judges of late) the Records for a Term in one of the ſuperior Courts might be put and carried in a mans pocket, being but one ſingle bundle of Rolls, containing about twenty or thirty Rolls, and yet ſome of them fraught with many Continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances, (moſt of which long ſince have been rendred uſeleſs by the Statute of <hi>Jeofailes;</hi>) But now there be thouſands of Rolls in ſome one or more of the Terms in the year in ſome of ſuch ſuperior Courts, containing three great Bundles of Rolls, ſo much as two or three Por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters can conveniently carry on their ſhoulders, the moſt part of which
<pb n="27" facs="tcp:118516:14"/>containing vain Entries, Imparlances, and Continuances thereof, and of Proces of Philazers, and Exigenters, and Continuances thereof, and Counts, and Declarations, and other Pleadings upon the ſame, which after have been again recorded in a ſuperfluous manner, and other things which might very well have been forborn, being only contrived for the only gain or Exactions of Prothonatories, Philazers, &amp; Exigent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, their Clerks, and other Clerks; which Records (without the expect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of further gain of ſuch Officers) in every Court might be contrived to be ſo ſhort as formerly they have been: For now in Criminal Cauſes againſt Felons (who be to loſe their lives) the Clerks (who draw and record the Proces againſt them) have done and can do and contrive all the matter againſt ſuch a Felon ſo ſhort, that about eight or ten of the ſame uſually have been written in one hour; but if any Criminal Cauſe have come in queſtion not touching the life of man, ſuch an one hath been put to exceſſive charges, eſpecially when the Cauſe hath been removed into the Capital Office (formerly called the Crown Office) where they have been ſqueezed to the purpoſe by be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing compelled to pay for writing of Records ſeveral times over more then neceſſary, and to pay ſometimes double, and at other times tre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble ſo much, as for Records are uſually paid.</p>
               <p n="5">5. <hi>That there may be a Seal (as anciently there hath been) in ſome peculiar place, to be for every of the Courts before mentioned, to be come to at all times of every working day, by any Clerk of every ſuch particular Court ſo to be approved of, or allowed, as before is mentioned, there to ſeal with the ſame any Writ of courſe, without paying or giving any thing for ſo doing.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If this were done and Enacted, then need not any man ſtay ſo ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny weeks for a General Seal, and ſometimes pay 5 <hi>s.</hi> 10 <hi>s.</hi> 20 <hi>s.</hi> 30 <hi>s.</hi> or more, for a private Seal, as too often hath been uſed, and the Mono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poly of the Green Seal Offices and Officers thereof aboliſhed, and the Great Seal to be only for ſuch things as ſhall go or paſs through the hands of the Attorney General, or Soliciter General, and approved by the State.</p>
               <p>That ſuch Attorney and Soliciter might only attend their places for their Salaries or Penſions as formerly, and now in ſome other Nations, and not intermeddle with any other thing, in putting poor men to exceſſive charges in retaining them for their counſel with extraordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nary large Fees or rewards or others powerful with ſuch Fees or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards to ballance them, or otherwiſe ſuch poor people have been ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly cruſhed, though their Cauſes have been never ſo juſt, and many
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:118516:15"/>ſuch poor people (who have made very hard ſhift to procure mony to retain ſuch counſel) have thereby been much impoveriſhed, and ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver recovered it during their lives.</p>
               <p>And if theſe things were obſerved (as anciently) by the Attorney General, and Serjeants, Solicitors, &amp;c. of this Republique, then would they attend the publique buſineſs of this Nation only, and not be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tangled with any other, and grow expert in State buſineſs, as well as thoſe in ſuch like Imployment in other Nations: And then if this were performed, and other the beſt learned of this Nation put to their Salaries only, and held ſtrictly to their duties, in a ſhort time this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion would exceedingly flouriſh, and (all ſelf-end-gain being layd aſide) would be a means to bring the moſt wiſe and judicious of this Nation to become honeſt, or at leaſt to joyn with ſuch as be or ſhall be ſo; and then if the Advice and Directions of ſuch be obſerved, there can be no doubt but this Nation may be as happy, or more then any other, and be a pattern for them.</p>
               <p n="6">6. <hi>That after any Writ of Justice, with ſuch Count, Declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, or other thing therewith, before mentioned, be or ſhall be deli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered to any Sheriff or Sheriffs, his or their Deputy or Deputies, he or they ſhall or may be Authorized to ſeize and take the Cattel, Goods or Chattels of any againſt whom the ſame be or ſhall be a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>warded, and keep the ſame until Judgment and Execution be or ſhall be upon the ſame, or ſufficient Sureties or Manucaptors found by the Defendant or Defendants in the ſame, to ſatisfie the Debt or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand which ſhall be recovered upon the ſame, and that ſuch Sureties or Manucaptors ſhall be liable ſo to do, or attach or ſtay any Debt, Duty or Demand owing or due to the Defendant in ſuch cauſe by any other or others, and that recovery upon ſuch Writ of Juſtice, if the ſame be not ſatisfied by ſuch Defendant, ſuch perſon from whom ſuch Debt or Duty ſhall be due, ſhall ſatisfie the ſame, and that the ſame courſe may be taken and the ſame proceedings in any of the ſuperior Courts uſually held at Weſtminster.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>By this, if the ſame were Enacted, may be gained in many ſums of mony very cheap with eaſe and ſpeed, and many chargeable Tryals abated or taken away, and many ſuch like Debts and Duties ſaved, which formerly have been loſt by reaſon of many wilful delays and fraudulent practiſes of Sheriffs and their Deputies.</p>
               <p n="7">7. <hi>That in all ſuch Cauſes (wherein Rule or Orders of courſe have been uſually given) a general Rule or Order (as anciently hath-been) may be made in all Cauſes of the ſame nature in every Court.</hi>
                  <pb n="29" facs="tcp:118516:15"/>If this were Enacted, the Monopoly of offices of Regiſters, and Draw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers and Enterers of Rules and Orders, and the Officers thereof, would fall, and thereby many intricacies and doubts in proceedings taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, whereby the people may the better underſtand the proſecution in their Cauſes or Suits; and they, or their Attorneys, or Solicitors, boldly ask or demand their Rights, without fear of them, or their Superiors, and go chearfully and with eaſe about their buſineſs, and have the better knowledg of the proceedings thereof, and not to be troubled to wait or attend<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or be checked or contradicted by the cheating proud Officers in ſuch Offices, as they have been too often many times in divers Cauſes and Suits, their Attorneys or Solicitors having been checked and taunted at, and made (as if it were) ſlaves by ſuch, for matters of Proceedings and Entries in ſuch Offices happen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing amiſs, which have been occaſioned ſometimes by the negligence, at other times by the wilful miſtake of ſuch Officers, for their own Exactions; whereby divers proceedings in ſuch Cauſes and Suits, after much charges and trouble in the ſame, have been avoyded, and the parties to ſuch Cauſes and Suits put to new trouble and charges about the ſame; and yet, by reaſon of the powerfulneſs of ſuch Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers in ſuch Courts, no remedy hath been had againſt them, but ſuch poor Clerks, Attorneys or Solicitors checked by ſome, and jeered at by others of the Aſſociates and Confederates of ſuch Exacting Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers, for the knavery and neglect of the ſame Officers.</p>
               <p n="8">8. <hi>That a certainty in general of Coſts after every Judgment of every reſpective nature given or pronounced in every Court may be, and that the Judgment may be entred accordingly (as anciently hath been, before uſeleſs innovations crept in) without waiting on</hi> Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thonatories, <hi>or their Deputies, unleſs in ſome extraordinary Cauſes, and then if the ſame be not, nor ſhall be agreed upon by parties on both ſides after Notes delivered each to other, in manner and form as is before mentioned in ſome of the former</hi> Propoſals <hi>or</hi> Propoſitions, <hi>then, and not before, the ſame to be aſcertained by ſuch</hi> Prothonatory <hi>or Deputy, or moved for, to ſuch Court, and thereby done and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fected; or that four or more of the ancient Clerks of every Court, to be eſteemed of moſt ability and honeſt, may ſit every Term for every of the Superior or ſuch like Courts termly held in Office of the ſame, and there two or more of them ſit two or three hours in every Juridical day in the afternoon, and hear and determine (if they can) the doubts of and in every Cauſe which ſhall be brought before them, in which never a one of them ſhall have any intereſt (as in divers
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:118516:16"/>Courts have been anciently) or otherwiſe to certifie their Opinious thereof to ſuch COurt: but this to be only for ſuch Cauſes in which the Suiters and their Agents be ſo ignorant, that they be not able to draw or procure the drawing of their Cauſes into writing, accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the before mentioned Propoſitions.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>If this wre Enacted, then need not Suitors in ſuch Courts, or their Attorneys, wait ſo long upon <hi>Prothonatories,</hi> or their Deputies, to have or procure Coſts after Verdicts or Inqueſts to be ſigned, very many times ſuch Attorneys waiting long upon ſuch Officers bare<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>headed in the cold, like Slaves or Vaſſals, as Counſel uſe to do, to be heard to move at the Bars: And then alſo may Suitors have Attorneys or Clerks, who never uſe to give, but abhor giving gratuities or new-years gifts (or as they may more properly be called, Bribes) to any of ſuch <hi>Prothonatories</hi> or their Deputies, chearfully, without trouble or ſlaviſh fear, procure Judgments after ſuch Verdicts and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſts to be entred or ſigned, without giving to ſuch Attorneys or Solicitors, who have uſed and do uſe to give ſuch rewards, gratuities or gifts, and to give unto them exceſsive Fees and other great rewards, to have great and extraordinary Coſts taxed, which by ſuch means uſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally have been accompliſhed by ſuch like Attorney or Clerk, who for the moſt part have been of the more ignorant ſort in Clerkſhip, they only having betaken themſelves to, and ſtudyed to perform ſuch things, and neglected Clerkſhip; and for ſuch knavery, and knaviſh intentions, have been had in higher eſteen, then any houeſt and learned Attorney or Clerk, which hath brought an <hi>Odium</hi> up the Law, Clerk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip and honeſt Lawyers and Clerks of this Nation, who have deteſted ſuch unlawful actions and inventions, and gone on in their buſineſs in an honeſt and ordinary way, and not (as ſuch knaviſh and diſhoneſt Attorneys and Clerks have done) learned, or gone about to leam, the meaning of the Takers or Receivers of ſuch rewards, gratuities or gifts by their looks, in ſuch manner as Solicitors have done of Maſters of the <hi>Chancery,</hi> and other Referrees and Favorite Counſelf of thoſe beofre whom they have moved, and uſed to give ſuch Rewards, Gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tuities or Gifts.</p>
               <p>And beſides, Judges may very well, out of ſuch their large Salaries, provide ſuch <hi>Prothonatories</hi> and pay them; for now they have and hold their place under the chief of ſuch Judges, who formerly had a larger Salary then any of the other, ſufficient to pay for writing; all which then in ſuch Courts was neceſſary to be written, of which there is no other doubt to be made but it was that ways imployed,
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:118516:16"/>and then would all references be ſpeedily ended at every particular time appointed, and none to ſtay or wait long the one after the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, as hath been uſual for ſeveral days the one after the other, and then there would not be ſo much weight layd upon one mans back, being almoſt enough to break the back of a Miller Load-horſe; but this to be for ſuch Cauſes only in which the Suitors and their Agents be ſo ignorant, that they be not able to have the doubt in their Suit to be drawn into writing in the nature of a Caſe, in ſuch manner and form as is mentioned in the before mentioned <hi>Propoſitions</hi> or <hi>Propo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſals</hi> for that purpoſe: And this courſe will encourage many ancient Clerks to be and endevor to be learned and expert, as they have been in ancient times, when they have inſtructed the Judges when they have been miſtaken, and have ſpoken to the Judges in thoſe times with boldneſs, and by them have been patiently heard, and their In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtructions obſerved by the ancient Judges in thoſe times, who were milde and meek, as formerly hath been mentioned, and uſed not to check, munt, ſnarl at, and daſh Practizers and Clerks before them out of countenance, as hath been uſed of late, and by ſome who have been negligent enough at ſome times, and have at the Tryals in ſome Cauſes, and having been overcharged with — uttered up that — in an unſeemly manner, and at other times have jeered honeſt men out of their juſt Cauſes, and have daunted their Witneſſes by jeering and otherwiſe. And alſo, if this oighth <hi>Propoſition</hi> were Enacted, then would the common uſes of Attorneys, and eſpecially of thoſe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing from places far diſtant from <hi>Westminster,</hi> be prevented, which have been as followeth, (that is to ſay) in their Travels to and from <hi>Westminster</hi> they have (as it were) hanged and drawn among them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves; for when they have met at their uſual Inns,<note place="margin">Thieves dividing the ſpoyl.</note> they have agreed to go to Tryals and enter Judgments in as many Cauſes only asby In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formation of one another they have thought would be ſearched for or after, (having not been above the tenth part of their Cauſes,) and yet they have cauſed their Clyents to pay for all the other, as if Tryals and Judgments reſpectively have been in the ſame, and as if they had payd unto the Monopolizing Officers to the moſt, according to their Extortions:<note place="margin">One cheat dcceiving another.</note> and by ſuch means they who could keep themſelves from being queſtioned by ſuch Monopolizers for taking that which they clairned to belong to them by giving Rewards to the Favotites of their Superiors to work them off, ſuch Reward-givers have grown great in Riches, unto which ſuch (who have not been skilled in ſuch ſubtilties, or have been learned) have never attained.</p>
               <p n="9">
                  <pb n="32" facs="tcp:118516:17"/>9. <hi>That any ſuch Clerk before mentioned may write the whole Record, which any perſon ſhall have to be tryed at any Aſſizes, upon any Iſſue or Iſſues joyned or to be joyned in any ſuch Superior Court; and that the ſame may be examined as before is mentioned, and ſign<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, if well done, in ſuch manner as before is mentioned; and that he or they ſo examining, or ſigning, ſhall take nothing for doing the ſame; and that a common form ſhall be contrived for Writs in every ſuch caſe, to be affixed to every of ſuch Records, Authorizing and Commanding the Judges of ſuch Aſſizes to Try or hear the Tryal of ſuch Iſſues, and to do all things for a Judg neceſſary to be done about the Tryal of the ſame.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>For this may the chief Judg or Juſtice, or any other Judg, do, if they will: for in the Statute, whereby ſuch Tryals were created, it is Enacted, That ſuch Records to be tryed ſhould be ſent to the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices of Aſſize, to be tryed by the Court or chief Juſtice thereof, where the Cauſe to be tryed is depending, and no Fees ſet what, they ſhould take for the ſame: whereby it may be clearly gathered, that the intent of that Law was, that ſuch Records ſhould be ſent down into the Countries to be tryed (without ſuch charge as now, by making new Records thereof, for which there is no mention made in the Statute) and after returned thither for Judgments to be entred upon the ſame, which may very well and eaſily be done, if the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular Records of every Cauſe might be diſtinctly kept by themſelves, and Filed together, and not to be bound up in Books or bundles, till after final Judgment or ſentence: and why may not any man have his Judgment entred upon the ſame Record, to be kept and filed, and not to be at the charge againſt his Will to have them written again, moſt of them being either ſatisfied or payd ſhortly after Judgment entred? But if any new precedent happen, then it is and will be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient that all the proceedings thereupon ſhould be entred at large, and bound up into books or bundles, but at the publique charge only; and then care will be taken that no ſuch books or bundles ſhall be ſtuffed with ſuperfluous matter, and thereby made long, and the State be put to unneceſſary charges by ſuch Entries, and the People to much trouble in ſearching for Records in ſuch Court; and as concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning the Examination of ſuch Records. and Proceedings, there will be little need, if the <hi>Propoſitions</hi> or <hi>Propoſals</hi> for Amendment of Proceedings in Law do take effect.</p>
               <p n="10">10. <hi>That if any Sheriff, Bayliff, or Serjeant at the Mace, ſhall require, exact, or take any exceſſive ſum of Mony of any (who ſhall
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:118516:17"/>deſire or require him to execute any Writ or Warrant, according to his duty, when he may attend the ſame; and go about it without dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger) then ſhall ſuch Sheriff, Bayliff, and Serjeant, forfeit and loſe to the party grieved thereby, the value of his juſt Debt r Duty, for recovery of which by ſuch Writ he proſecuteth.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>And that if any ſuch Officer ſhall take or exact any exceſſive Mony of any Debitor or Defendant (by colour of ſtaying or waiting, or for Lodging or Dyet) whereby ſuch Debtor or Defendant is diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled to ſatisfie the Creditor or Demandant his Debt or Demand, then ſuch Officer to forfeit to ſuch Creditor or Demandant ten times the value of that which the ſaid Officer ſhall ſo exact or take.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <q>If this were Enacted, then neither would nor could ſuch Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers afford to buy their Offices at ſuch dear Rates as they have uſed of latter years, for making up of which they have uſed great and grievous Extortions, whereby many poor people have been utterly ruined, and others much impoveriſhed, and divers others put to exceſſive charges and trouble, to as much or more then the value of that which they ſued for; ſuch Officers moſt commonly, when they have had Executions to ſerve, having exacted of the Proſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor ſometimes half, at other times a third, and moſt commonly a fourth part of the Debt or Demand, before they have or would ſerve ſuch Execution againſt the goods or body of any; and when they have had Writs to deliver to any, poſſeſſion of Meſſuages or Tenements, they have uſually taken and exacted of the Proſecutor one years Rent thereof, or ſecurity for the ſame, before they would go about it; and beſides, if the Proſecutors have not by themſelves or Solicitors danced attendance, and waited on ſuch Officers, they neither have nor would ſerve ſuch Executions, until towards the end of the year of their remaining in Office, taking Bribes in the mean time of the Defendant for forbearing ſuch Execution; and thoſe, who have made it (as it were) a Trade to be ſuch Officer or Deputy from year to year in onc County or other for many years to<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gether, and having by their ſecret Combination, Practices and Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>federacies with their Agents or Brethren in Iniquity, have by them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, their Alies, Servants, or private Creatures, took the benefit of the moſt part, or a great part of the benefit of ſuch Offices for di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers years, and have grown ſo cunning and ſubtil in the ſame, that they have ſo ſeeretly extorted and exacted great ſums of Mony by colour of ſuch Offices, which none but ſuch as they, could diſcover; whereby they have given, and could afford to give for ſuch Offices,
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:118516:18"/>more then any honeſt man, whereby ſeldom or never any honeſt have medled, or would meddle with any ſuch Office, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſuch Officers (ſo commonly continuing in Office) have taken as it were a yearly Rent of many Out-liers and Fugitives in their Counties, skulking and lurking there, and never would arrreſt nor have arreſted them, unleſs the Proſecutors or their Agents have been at their heels; and by theſe means many juſt Debts have been loſt by delay, and the parties ſo lurking, and skulking, and bribing, ſpent as much or more then would ſatisfie the Creditor, and utterly un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>done themſelves, their wives and children, in ſo living in expence and idleneſs for many years together.</q>
               </p>
               <p>And then alſo would be prevented the occaſion of ſuch Sheriffs, and other Officers before with them mentioned, exacting and extort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſuch great Sums of Mony out of many poor Defendants (who have not ſo bribed ſuch Officers, and againſt whom ſuch Officers have had Executions)<note n="†" place="margin">
                     <p>A Sherift lately ſeized in Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution a Barn of Corn worth 40 <hi>l.</hi> he ſet one man to threſh it, and two Bayliffs to overſee the work, who ſold the Corn to main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain themſelves with good drink and victuals; ſo that the Barn of Corn payd but about forty ſhillings of the Debt.</p>
                     <p>The ſaid Sheriſt lately ſeized upon a Defendants Cows, Horſes and Sheep; the Cows brought in dayly profit by their Milk, the Horſes by their dayly working, (ſo long as they were able to go on their lege,) the Sheep by be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing folded: every night and kept in the common field, where the Sherift had no right of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon,) yet the Defendant, when he redeemed his Cattel, was com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pelled to pay for all their keep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, as if they had done nothing but gone in Paſture-ground.</p>
                  </note> by ſelling the Cattel and Goods and Chattals at under-rates, ſome to half, at other times to leſs, of the true value thereof, to ſome of their Agents, with whom (by ſecret combination and practice between them, which neither hath nor could be diſcovered) they have ſhared and divided the ſpoyl, and at other times by work<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and laboring Cattel, and uſing and imploy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Goods and Chattals of ſuch Defendants to and for the uſe of them and their Aſſociates, whereby the Cattel, Goods and Chattals have been much impaired, and ſome of them ſpoyled or quite worn out; and yet many times ſuch extorting Officers have been ſo impudent, and voyd of all conſcience or honeſty, that (if the buſineſs be compounded, ſo that ſuch Defendant were to have ſuch Goods, Chattals and Cattel again) they have cauſed ſuch poor Defendants to pay great Sums of Mony for the keeping and Stoage of ſuch Goods and Chattals, and feeding of ſuch Cattel.</p>
               <p>And then ſuch extorting Officers would be prevented of their con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinual uſage of defrauding many poor people (who have come to them for Writs, and others to whom they have offered themſelves to ſue out Writs for) by going to ignorant Attorneys or Officers (who
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:118516:18"/>know the courſe of Actions as little as themſelves) to take out ſuch Writs in Treſpaſs, when the Cauſes have been for great Debts or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands, who ſometimes have made forth ſuch Writs, and thereby ſuch Officers have Arreſted divers Defendants (of whom, or their Sureties, they have taken good ſecurity for the appearance of ſuch Defendants) but after (by reaſon of Bribes given to ſuch Officers by ſuch Defendants) ſuch Officers have ſometimes forborn to tell ſuch ſimple people (who have ſo firſt gone to ſuch Officers for ſuch Writs, before they have adviſed with, or acquainted any honeſt and learned Counſel Clerk or Attorney in their Cauſes) of ſuch Arreſt done, till after ſuch Defendants have appeared at the day of their appearance, and either foyſted in common Bayl, for want of marking the Rolls, or calling for good Bayl, or otherwiſe: in ſome Courts have non-ſuited the Cauſe, and obtained Coſts againſt ſuch ſimple people, both which have uſually been done and allowed by the courſe and practice of the Superior Courts, or otherwiſe (when ſuch appearance and good Bayl hath been called for) ſuch Officers have forborn the return of ſuch Writs and Warrants thereupon, and Bonds many times half, at other times a whole year, and divers times ſeveral years, and ſome of them after the return of ſuch Writs have ſtood out Amerciaments for as long a time, and divers times till many Debts have been loſt, and ſuch Amerciaments have not redounded to the benefit of the Suitors, but to the King, or &amp;c. and after ſuch Officers have ſtood out ſo long after appearance, they have got off ſuch Amerciaments for very little.</p>
               <p>And ſome of them have bragged and boaſted, that they have ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained Patents for the benefit of Amerciaments within their Juriſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictions to their own uſes, and that therefore they have not cared how many Amerciaments have been impoſed upon, eſtreated or ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tracted out againſt them (ſaying, the more, the better for their advan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tage,) and have jeered the Suitors, and ſaid, that if they did not comply with them the ſaid Sheriffs or Officers, to their liking, by giv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of them ſuch high Rewards as they have demanded, or retained ſome Attorney of their Aſſociates or Servants (who uſe to ſqueeze and wring much Mony out of their Clyents in an exceſſive manner, and with whom ſuch Sheriffs or Officers uſe to ſhare) then ſuch Suitors ſhould have little benefit of their buſineſſes; ſome of ſuch Officers (who have gained peculiar liberties therein) often reporting, that they can do what they pleaſe in moſt Cauſes within their li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties.</p>
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:118516:19"/>
               <p>And many times ſuch Officers and Clyents have gone to ſuch At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torneys or Solicitors as have been Aſſociates of ſuch Officers, who have made out Warrants without Writs, or otherwiſe ſuch Officers have Areſted the Defendants without Writs, and then took Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, or (as they may more fitly be called) Bribes, of both Plaintiffs and Defendants, in endevoring to end their buſineſs; and threatning Plaintiffs, that if they would not ſtand to their award, they ſhould have little good ſucceſs in their buſineſſes; and by uſing the Defend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ants (being ſimple) ruggedly, and terrifying them, they have wrought them into Commpoſitions, and ſhared in the Debts and Demands, and in many that have not been, they have gained a fourth, third, and ſometimes half of ſuch Debts and Demands, and by ſuch means have cauſed themſelves to be made both Judges, Attorneys, or Solicitors, and Bayliffs, in ſuch Cauſes: And in many Cauſes (wherein they have graſped into their hands the ſuing out of ſuch Writs) and in ſuch Cauſes (wherein they could not procure Compoſitions or Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferences) they have cauſed the Defendants to retain Attorneys being Aſſociates of ſuch Officers, with whom they have ſhared in their Fees; and in neither of both theſe caſes laſt mentioned any Writs at all have been ſued out, and yet the Clyents have payd for Writs; by which menas Mony hath been extorred and exacted out of Cly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ents for more Writs then have iſſued out of the Superior Court, by which means the honeſt people of this Nation have been much de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>frauded for many years together.</p>
               <p>And many ſuch Officers (that is to ſay) Underſheriffs, Bayliffs, and Serjeants, when they have Arreſted honeſt meaning men, had them to Tippling houſes, or houſes of them and their Aſſociates, have ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torted and exacted much Money out of them, by threatning of them to carry them to priſon; and thoſe (who have not rewarded them to their liking, or could not) they have drag'd nd hurryed to priſon, hunching and kicking them, though they have never reſiſted nor of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fered to reſiſt ſuch Officers, nor given them any ill words: And when ſuch Officers have been imployed only to take appearance upon Arreſt, they have conſtrained the perſons Arreſted to pay down the Attorneys Fees, and mony by them to be layd out in appearances, in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the hands of Officers; and then would they ſeldom or never pay the ſame to ſuch Officers, if the buſineſs proceeded, or reſtore the ſame to the Defendants, if the ſame were ended; and when ſome few have gotten ſome part of ſuch mony out of ſuch Huckſters hands, they have ſpent as much, and ſometimes more, then the value thereof,
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:118516:19"/>beſides the ſuſtaining of great trouble in moving Courts by Counſel, and complaining to Judges and Juſtices, by which means ſuch Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cers have kept to their own uſes ſuch mony, and the poor parties ſo Arreſted conſtrained to procure ſo much more for their appear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances.</p>
               <p>And further, if all the <hi>Propoſitions</hi> or <hi>Propoſals</hi> before mention<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed were Enacted, beſides the benefit which thereby would accrue to the honeſt people of this Nation, as before is mentioned; theſe bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fits and advantages hereafter following would redound to the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lique Advantage; and the enſuing Inconveniencies and Miſchiefs (which have much injured and prejudiced the honeſt people of this Nation) be prevented and taken away.</p>
               <p>For then it would be again as in ancient times, when Parliaments have been once every year, and more often when occaſion in thoſe times have happened, being when Kings were vertuous, and abhorred vice, and had care of the then honeſt people of this Nation (accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing as to their then light they were) as of themſelves, when the peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple had Juſtice equally, and without delay, done by their Equals, and thereby continued in great quiet, but that they were beſotted and beguiled by the <hi>Prieſt,</hi> as before is mentioned, who for ſuch their actings deſervedly fell; and it is thought others (who have done as bad or worſe then they on a ſudden) will do the like, if they do not timely repent and amend.</p>
               <p>And then would again the Members of Parliaments, or Repreſen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tatives, be only of the moſt honeſt and diſcreet of the people of this Nation, and no other, equally and impartially Elected without trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble or charge to any, as formerly hath been, and diſpatch all buſineſs coming before them ſpeedily, (the one of them ſeldom contradicting the other,) as hath been in thoſe ancient times, without ſitting of full Parliament or Repreſentative any extraordinary long time together, but conclude all buſineſs for them neceſſary to be done (which no o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Courts could remedy) within a Month, ſix weeks, or two Months time at the moſt (unleſs upon extraordinary occaſions) be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Adjournment, Prorogation or Ending, which cauſed the Engliſh Laws to be accounted the beſt in Chriſtendom (and deſervedly, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore Innovations crept in,) and then were few Motions in reſpect of the extraordinary multitudes which have been of late made by Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vorite Counſel, or any other Motions by any other the Attorneys or Clerks, unleſs it were in caſes extraordinary by honeſt &amp; learned Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel, and not by Favorites to begin a Cauſe, and have a large Fee for ſo
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:118516:20"/>doing, uſually only ſaying, ſuch an one is Plaintiff, and ſuch an one is Defendant, and then an honeſt learned Lawyer have uſually gone on with the ſame throughly, or otherwiſe ſuch Favorites have or could ſay little more, and ſome of them have not been of ability, or capable to ſay any more, though they have received extraordinary large Fees double, treble, ſometimes fourfold of that which ſuch honeſt Lawyers have had; which Favorites the Suitors have been conſtrained to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, or otherwiſe ſuch learned and honeſt Lawyers have ſeveral days the one after the other waited, till ſome of them have been wearyed out, and given the buſineſs over, and others, who have attended to be heard, have took as much pains as a Porter hath in going of errands, and earning as much mony in ſuch time: and beſides, ſuch honeſt Lawyers, when they have long waited and have been heard, they have had little or no fruit of their Motions, but have been flammed off, baffled, and girt up, and checked, before they have been half heard out their Motion, and have been ſent home with a ſleeveleſs errand, and been diſcouraged.</p>
               <p>And thereby the Favorites, by Alliances or yearly preſents, gratui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties or new-years gifts, learning the meaning of their Superiors by their looks, have ingroſſed up all or the moſt part of the gains in eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Cauſe, and thereby they and their Superiors have climbed to a great height in few years; and many times when one Suitor having retain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed one, two, or three Counſel, to plead his Cauſe at the Aſſizes and other places, where ſeveral Counſel have uſed to attend, to the number of twenty or thirty, or ſometimes more at ſeveral Bars, ſuch Suitor hath been baffled out, and loſt his Cauſe, unleſs he had retained half ſuch Counſel, by reaſon ſome crafty perſon have cauſed the Record of ſuch Cauſe to be carryed to another Bar, where ſuch Suitor nor his Counſel have expected the Cauſe ſhould be tryed; and many times the principal Counſel of ſuch Suitor being called to, and at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tending another Cauſe at another Bar, and from the Bar where ſuch Suitors Cauſe was expected to be tryed; and then when the Cauſe of ſuch Suitor hath been called, and he deſiring the Judg to ſtay until his Counſel came, or that the Cauſe might be tryed where they were to attend other Tryals, the Judges, before whom ſuch Cauſes have been to be tryed, have denyed to admit the ſame, caſting an angry look upon ſuch Suitor, ſaying, there were other Counſel enough whom they might retain (nodding towards Favorite Dunces ſtanding in ſight,)<note place="margin">☞</note> and thereupon ſuch poor Suitors have been conſtrained to retain Lawyers of mean Judgment on a ſudden, who could not underſtand
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:118516:20"/>their Cauſes ſoon enough, and ſome not at all, nor capable thereof; and ſuch Cauſes, having been tryed in the abſence of ſuch honeſt and learned Counſel retained and inſtructed at the firſt, have gone and paſſed againſt ſuch Suitors, having had the beſt and moſt right to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover in ſuch Cauſe: And when any of ſuch Favorite Lawyers have failed in ſuch their preſents or gifts, at the uſual time of the preſent<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſame, have grown out of favor; and after they ſo failing, have had a grin or a wry face from ſome of ſuch Superiors; they have not come into favor again a long time, and ſome of them never, which hath cauſed moſt of them conſtantly to continue the ſame, and by thoſe means grow the more expert in ſuch their Combinations (the more to keep others, who do not uſe ſuch dealing, ignorant thereof) and be ſuffered to foam out non-ſence, and lye, bark, brawl, and wrangle as they have pleaſed (when others of ability have not been ſuffered ſcarce to ſpeak three or four words in a cauſe) and thereby to gain the affection of Suitors in ſuch Cauſes: and ſometimes ſuch Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vorites, though they have been many on a ſide, have not dared to ſpeak a word more in any Cauſe after they have received a private look from ſome Superior, which none other but themſelves have underſtood, which is thought hath been when ſome ſuch Superior, or ſome of his Alies or Private Creatures, have graſped and hooked in more then ſuch Favorites have received for their Fees,<note place="margin">Coventry, <hi>and</hi> Mancheſter</note> wherein <hi>Coventry</hi> and <hi>Queen Beſſe</hi> have been accounted very expert.</p>
               <p>And by ſuch means other under or petty Officers to Inferiors un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the high Superiors (who have learned the skill to give Rewards or Bribes to thoſe Superiors, to keep them from queſtioning by ſuch Inferiors) when they have done amiſs, have gained much.</p>
               <p>And then would Suitors know what evidence they were to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce at Tryals, and not to be triced or non-ſuited on a ſudden, many times the one after the other, as many times hath fallen out, to the infinite gains of ſuch ignorant Favorite Lawyers, and great damage to the honeſt people; neither would Juries be puſled with multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudes of Iſſues at a time, but all Cauſes tryed in an eaſie way, as hath been in the beſt time.</p>
               <p>And then could not ſuch Inferior and the greater Monopolizing Officers before mentioned, by the favor which they have gained of their Superiors, by contributing to them part of the gains of ſuch innovated and extorting Offices before mentioned, take ſuch occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, as they have done, to increaſe their Exactions by colour of ſuch Offices, to cauſe Orders to be made, whereby many Miſchiefs and
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:118516:21"/>Inconveniencies have faln upon Suitors in Cauſes; and when com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint hath been thereof, they have cauſed the poor Proſecutors thereof to be blamed and checked for the faults or neglects of ſuch Officers and their Superiors, and ſtill kept ſuch Proſecutors under, that they have not dared to complain, or ſo much as publiquely reveal what hath beendone amiſs by ſuch Monopolizing Officers, or their Superiors.</p>
               <p>And then would the Vagrant Favorite Counſel forbear wandering abroad into ſeveral Counties, and extorting upon the people there, and putting them to great trouble, as they have too often uſed.</p>
               <p>And further, and laſtly, (upon obſervation and ſerious conſiderati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of the whole matter before expreſſed) We conceive, and are in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed by others (with whom we have conferred) that by the Ten laſt <hi>Propoſitions</hi> (if the ſame were Enacted) would yearly be ſaved to the honeſt People of this Nation above fifty thouſand pounds [50000 <hi>l.</hi>] (which annually formerly have been exacted from them by undeſerving corrupt Officers, over and above the before menti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oned Sums) by rendering of ſome of the Offices and Officers, by and in thoſe Ten <hi>Propoſitions</hi> mentioned (who formerly have unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully exacted yearly divers thouſands of pounds) meerly uſeleſs, and to have been inconvenient and miſchievous; and reducing others of them uſeful, from divers thouſands of pounds, to four hundred pounds, and others to a competent gain, according to their deſerts, as anciently hath been, before Innovations and Exactions crept in (being contrived and obtained by Monopoliſts, and Buyers and Sellers of Offices and Juſtice) without Parliament-Authority, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trary to the Law.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>See the Table or the Particulars of the Five millions ſeven hundred ſixty eight thouſand ſeven hundred and ſeven pounds</hi> [5768707 l.] <hi>formerly yearly Exacted and Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torted, and Loſſes in Estates every year heretofore, an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nually hereafter ſaved and prevented, caſt up together in</hi> Pag. 21. <hi>of this Book.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="postscript">
            <pb n="41" facs="tcp:118516:21"/>
            <head>Poſtſcript.</head>
            <p>WE deſire all the honeſt People of this Nation further to take notice, that we conceive our ſelves bound to publiſh our Ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſervations upon what we have with deliberation plainly ſeen to be intolerable Abuſes and Oppreſſions layd upon the People of this <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monwealth.</hi> It is no ſmall grief unto us, to minde what little Juſtice we have ſeen and heard of, exerciſed (in this our age) in Courts of Judicature; What is it but the want of reforming what is amiſs and unjuſt, which hath made our Troubles laſt ſo long in this our Native Country? Was it not the cauſe of the beginning and long continuing of Wars in <hi>Scotland?</hi> and hath it not been a means to continue Trou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles in <hi>Ireland?</hi> and is it not a great Encouragement now to Forreign People to make War againſt us, they underſtanding how many diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>contents are amongſt our ſelves? If Juſtice were but equally diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buted to all, who then would not advance the <hi>Republique</hi> with their Ingenuities, Purſes and Perſons? and would it not make our Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies at home to be at peace with us, and ſet to their helping hand to carry on juſt Deſigns? We cannot but call to remembrance, how (at the beginning of our Troubles) many thouſands were not backward to adventure their lives, and others cauſed their Mony, Plate, and Gold-rings to be freely made uſe of upon a Publique Account; and not all out of a religious principle only, but meerly for common Juſtice betwixt man and man, which being now not to be found, makes moſt of them repent of what they have done, ſaying, That <hi>if they had thought pulling down Kingly Government would have advantaged them no more, they would have been contented to be tyrannized over by a King ſtill;</hi> and the fault of all, we find to be put upon thoſe who are good for nothing but to ſet People together by the ears, and find out tricks to continue Law-Suits, even betwixt Father and Son, Husband and Wife, Brother and Brother, &amp;c. ſo long as they have any feathers upon their backs; and when they are made Beggers, by having their Suits ſpan out to the end of Suitors Purſes, with a Bottom of non-ſatisfaction woond up to the grieved party, let them go where they will. We cannot but obſerve, how almoſt all men are procuring large poſſeſſions to themſelves, and ſerv<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing their own ends, and neglecting the Publique, for which, at the firſt, Lives and Eſtates were not too much to adventure: many are
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:118516:22"/>apt to ſay, that they fear, Gold, Silver, or ſome rich Pad-locks are hung upon the mouths of divers perſons, who were wont to ſtand and ſpeak for righteous and juſt things to be done, but now of late have been ſilent and idle; who but the other day (as it were) were mighty ſtirring men, and nothing ſhould ſatisfie them until a Refor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation of palpable Abuſes. We alſo note, how many hard words our Rulers have abroad by reaſon of the ſlow proceedings in Regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lations; and it is thought the Favorite Lawyers and Monopoliſts are the Obſtructors. It is very ſad to conſider how many Complaints are heard abroad every day, we can hardly have the ſound of them out of our ears, nor our eyes long from beholding one or other, not only begger'd, but alſo deprived of part or all their Senſes by Oppreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, ſo that they are in no little better condition then mad, as is too apparant in theſe days. Why do we behold fawning, flattering, and diſſembling perſons (who were and ſtill are common Enemies to the Government of this <hi>Commonwealth</hi>) ſpeed better, then honeſt, godly, and conſcientious Chriſtians? Why is it that by favor ſo many Drunk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ards, Swearers,<note place="margin">Divers Officers have been ſo impu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dent, that they have not bluſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to ſay, they could not be half content with their Salary, without taking Gratuities.</note> notorious Lyars, &amp;c. are preferred to places of Truſt and great concernment, without any deſert at all; unto which per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, induſtrious, honeſt and religious people are made a prey, and by whom they are perplexed intolerably, unleſs Bribes be put into the Oppreſſors hands? As for proſecuting perſons for any miſdemeanor, it is neither ſafe nor profitable for any that are plain, down-right-deal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, conſcientious, and honeſt men; for an Offendor ſhall have favor enough for his mony: and unleſs the Proſecutor be as free as the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liquent, he is like to come off with a Scratcht face, and after the expence of much mony be liable to be ſued for what he hath done: So that we conceive <hi>Penal Statutes</hi> to be but of little uſe, except to get mony to Informers (who are accounted to be a Pack of Knaves living upon other mens labors) for there is ſcarce one to be found who will not take Bribes, and reſt contented, without caring to ſee the Juſtice of the Law executed, which encourageth notorious Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors much, knowing they can buy their peace with a ſmall ſum of mony when they pleaſe: But divers that are honeſt are ſo perplexed with the ſaid Informers (who uſually take rugged courſes with them, to fright them to give mony) that their lives are made burden<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſom to them, and their Eſtates not at their own, but unreaſonable creatures diſpoſing, who exact what they pleaſe, or elſe the Defendant ſhal be put to exceſſive charge and trouble, although his offence be but feigned, or not worth the naming. All theſe foregoing Grievances
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:118516:22"/>we conceive are occaſioned by reaſon of the want of honeſt, juſt, impartial, and able perſons to hear and determine Controverſies and Differences, whoſe place it is to inquire out the truth, and make a ſpeedy determination, without ſuffering the Proſecutor, or the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecuted, or both, to be undone by the invented tricks and devices of thoſe who mind nothing but their own exceſſive gain, and the Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples ruine; we ſee it apparant dayly, that a man had better loſe his Right, then contend for it with wilful, malicious, powerful, and rich Adverſaries; nay, if Equals go to Law (there being ſo many intrica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies in proceedings) both parties are at as much doubt which way the Cauſe will be carryed, as if they ſhould throw a Caſt at Dice for it. We cannot but ſtand amazed when we ſeriouſly conſider what griev<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous corruption there is almoſt in all places, where abuſed, afflicted and grieved parties ſhould make their conditions known with expec<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tation of Redreſs; and with what difficuly, charge and adventure Juſtice is procured! If that Officers abuſeth Suitors (by exacting or extorting mony, or by delay of ſuch buſineſs which their duty binds them to ſee performed, or otherwiſe) the grieved party cannot tell where to complain, but to thoſe from whom little Redreſs can be expected; ſo that he is conſtrained to be contented to be a ſlave to thoſe that are but Servants. All theſe before mentioned Oppreſſions, we are perſwaded, God will find out ſome way or other of deliverance from; but who it is that will be ſo far honored with the promoting of ſuch a glorious Work, we are not yet able to diſcern. Can we expect it from any but thoſe that are honeſt and godly? Whoſoever they be that have opportunities put into their hands, and makes not uſe of them, He that knoweth all things will lay ſuch perſons aſide, and make uſe of others that ſhall make a better improvement of their Talents which they are betruſted with. Theſe things being upon our hearts, we thought good to publiſh at the preſent, (reſerving divers other until hereafter ſome convenient opportunity preſents) being confident that moſt that are of publique ſpirits, unbiaſſed, honeſt and conſcientious, will (as we conceive they are bound) endevor the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moting of them, by uſing what lawful means the Lord ſhall direct them unto.</p>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>LONDON, Printed by <hi>John Macock,</hi> and are to be ſold by <hi>Francis Tyton</hi> at the three Daggers in <hi>Fleetſtreet,</hi> and <hi>Nathaniel Brook</hi> at the Angel in <hi>Cornhill.</hi> 1652.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
